<articles>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Philippines_is_culling_6500_hogs_after_Reston_ebolavirus_outbreak</source>
        <text>The Philippine Department of Agriculture (DA), local health and agricultural teams Sunday have started slaughtering, burning and burying roughly 6,500 hogs at a farm in Pandi, Bulacan in Central Luzon on Sunday after three farm workers became infected with Reston ebolavirus (ERV) of the virus group Ebola, as a precautionary measure and to protect the local livestock industry. "We culled around 300 heads—piglets and growers—in two and a half hours; we tried to start the process at 5 p.m. Sunday; after three hours we disposed of 442 hogs; that includes transporting the hogs to an area in the farm where they will be disposed of; with this rate and with some improvements in the procedure tomorrow, we expect to complete the depopulation by Wednesday,” Bureau of Animal Industry (BAI) head Davinio Catbagan said. "With the problems we encountered last night, we may go beyond Thursday," he added.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Pandi</name>
                <start>170</start>
                <end>175</end>
                <lat>14.87</lat>
                <lon>120.95</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pandi,_Bulacan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Central Luzon</name>
                <start>188</start>
                <end>201</end>
                <lat>15.47</lat>
                <lon>120.75</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Central_Luzon</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Bulacan</name>
                <start>177</start>
                <end>184</end>
                <lat>15</lat>
                <lon>121.08</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bulacan</page>
                </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Philippines_is_culling_6500_hogs_after_Reston_ebolavirus_outbreak</source>
        <text>The agriculture officials earlier announced that the depopulation will be carried out in a "humane" manner, following current Office international des épizooties (OIE) procedures that ensure protection of animal welfare in the Bulacan farm. According to Philippine Department of Health (DOH) Secretary Francisco Duque, the quarantine of the hog farm in Palauig, Manaoag, Pangasinan has been lifted after finding no traces of viral transmission. According to Yap, test results conducted by a joint mission of FAO, the World Animal Health Organization, WHO and their local counterparts, reveal that viral transmission continues to exist in Pandi hog farms, which is only 0.5% of the 13 million pigs raised throughout the country. DOH officials also say a pig farm worker in Cabanatuan in Nueva Ecija, who had no direct contact with sick hogs, has tested positive for Immunoglobulin G antibodies against the Reston ebolavirus, which is non-lethal, unlike the Zaïre, Bundibugyo, Côte d'Ivoire and Sudan strains, according to FAO.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Bulacan</name>
                <start>228</start>
                <end>235</end>
                <lat>15</lat>
                <lon>121.08</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bulacan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Manaoag</name>
                <start>363</start>
                <end>370</end>
                <lat>16.04</lat>
                <lon>120.48</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Manaoag,_Pangasinan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Pangasinan</name>
                <start>372</start>
                <end>382</end>
                <lat>15.92</lat>
                <lon>120.33</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pangasinan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Palauig</name>
                <start>354</start>
                <end>361</end>
                <lat>15.43</lat>
                <lon>120.05</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palauig</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Pandi</name>
                <start>639</start>
                <end>644</end>
                <lat>14.87</lat>
                <lon>120.95</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pandi,_Bulacan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Cabanatuan</name>
                <start>773</start>
                <end>783</end>
                <lat>15.48</lat>
                <lon>120.97</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cabanatuan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Nueva Ecija</name>
                <start>787</start>
                <end>798</end>
                <lat>15.58</lat>
                <lon>121</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nueva_Ecija</page>
            </location>
    </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Philippines_is_culling_6500_hogs_after_Reston_ebolavirus_outbreak</source>
        <text>Local police has also arrested four vendors and seized their 3,000 kilos of "botcha" (rotten pork meat or "double dead meat") at MC Market in Balintawak, Quezon City Wednesday evening, and allegedly delivered from Bulacan. The four suspects were charged for violation of the Consumer Act of the Philippines and Republic Act 9296 or the Meat Inspection Code. In December, international experts initially probed outbreak among Philippine pigs, wherein about 6,000 pigs at Pandi and Talavera farms were tested for the Reston ebolavirus. "There is no salmonella outbreak in Eastern Visayas, Region 8, said Dr. Archie Lluz, Chief of Regional Animal Disease and Diagnostic Laboratory of the Department of Agriculture in the region. But hog specimens from Tacloban and Babatngon, where 270 swine deaths and cases of sick pigs were reported, were examined by lab tests. The results revealed cutaneous "Pasteurella hemolytica", a type of bacterial infection which causes swine deaths due to loss of appetite, dehydration, fever and diarrhea.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Balintawak</name>
                <start>143</start>
                <end>153</end>
                <lat>14.63</lat>
                <lon>121.03</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Balintawak</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Quezon City</name>
                <start>155</start>
                <end>166</end>
                <lat>14.63</lat>
                <lon>121.03</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quezon_City</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Bulacan</name>
                <start>215</start>
                <end>222</end>
                <lat>15</lat>
                <lon>121.08</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bulacan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Pandi</name>
                <start>471</start>
                <end>476</end>
                <lat>14.87</lat>
                <lon>120.95</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pandi,_Bulacan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Talavera</name>
                <start>481</start>
                <end>489</end>
                <lat>15.58</lat>
                <lon>120.91</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Talavera,_Nueva_Ecija</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Eastern Visayas</name>
                <start>571</start>
                <end>586</end>
                <lat>11.24</lat>
                <lon>125.05</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eastern_Visayas</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Tacloban</name>
                <start>750</start>
                <end>758</end>
                <lat>11.24</lat>
                <lon>125</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tacloban</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Babatngon</name>
                <start>763</start>
                <end>772</end>
                <lat>11.42</lat>
                <lon>124.85</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Babatngon,_Leyte</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/US_soldier_who_died_after_serving_in_Liberia_tests_negative_for_Ebola</source>
        <text>Tests yesterday proved negative for Ebola on the remains of a US soldier who died in Texas after deployment to Liberia. The 24-year-old had been monitoring potential symptoms of the disease. The Killeen Police Department continues to investigate the soldier's death. He has not been named publicly. He died at his home near Fort Hood military base. Fort Hood said the soldier had been involved in constructing a hospital to combat Ebola in Africa, and returned to the US on emergency leave earlier this month.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Texas</name>
                <start>86</start>
                <end>91</end>
                <lat>31</lat>
                <lon>-100</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Texas</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Liberia</name>
                <start>112</start>
                <end>119</end>
                <lat>6.5</lat>
                <lon>-9.5</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liberia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>US</name>
                <start>63</start>
                <end>65</end>
                <lat>40</lat>
                <lon>-100</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Fort Hood</name>
                <start>325</start>
                <end>334</end>
                <lat>31.13</lat>
                <lon>-97.78</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fort_Hood</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Patient_under_evaluation_with_Ebola-like_symptoms_in_Washington_D.C.</source>
        <text>
A patient was admitted to a hospital in Washington, D.C. after showing Ebola-like symptoms, according to a statement yesterday by hospital spokeswoman Kerry-Ann Hamilton. Shady Grove Adventist Hospital in Rockville, Maryland admitted another patient with Ebola-like symptoms, but health officials there yesterday night later determined this person had malaria, not the Ebola virus. At the peak of Ebola countermeasures in Nigeria, almost 900 people there were monitored for the virus after contacting someone who was already sick.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Washington</name>
                <start>41</start>
                <end>51</end>
                <lat>38.90</lat>
                <lon>-77.01</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Washington,_D.C.</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Rockville</name>
                <start>206</start>
                <end>215</end>
                <lat>39.08</lat>
                <lon>-77.14</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rockville,_Maryland</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Maryland</name>
                <start>217</start>
                <end>225</end>
                <lat>39</lat>
                <lon>-76.7</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maryland</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Nigeria</name>
                <start>423</start>
                <end>430</end>
                <lat>8</lat>
                <lon>10</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nigeria</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Scottish_Ebola_nurse_Pauline_Cafferkey_%27critically_ill%27_says_Royal_Free_Hospital</source>
        <text>The Royal Free Hospital in London yesterday said a nurse suffering with complications after Ebola, Pauline Cafferkey, is "critically ill" after her condition deteriorated. Cafferkey, 39, was readmitted to an isolation unit at the Royal Free on the night of October 8–9 where she had spent time earlier in the year after contracting Ebola in Sierra Leone whilst treating patients with the infection. Cafferkey visited an out of hours GP clinic on October 5 where her symptoms were not linked to Ebola, before deciding to go to the Queen Elizabeth University Hospital in Glasgow on October 6 where she was treated at the hospital's infectious diseases unit. Two days later, she was flown by plane to the Royal Free. She is the only person known to suffer with Ebola in this way for a second time, which can remain in the body after an initial recovery.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>London</name>
                <start>28</start>
                <end>34</end>
                <lat>51.50</lat>
                <lon>-0.12</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/London</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Sierra Leone</name>
                <start>342</start>
                <end>354</end>
                <lat>8.5</lat>
                <lon>-11.5</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sierra_Leone</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Glasgow</name>
                <start>570</start>
                <end>577</end>
                <lat>55.85</lat>
                <lon>-4.25</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glasgow</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Bird_flu_outbreak_kills_birds_in_Krasnodar_region</source>
        <text>
Krasnodar, Russia officials said yesterday they have found roughly 4,000 dead wild birds in the region. Doctors identified the disease as bird flu subtype H5. Officials said the outbreak originated with coots in water reservoirs at the west of the region. The Krasnodar leading veterinary physician, George Gzhailidi, said the bird flu outbreak originated with coots in the Temryuk and Anapa. The region governor Alexander Nikolayevich Tkachyov said, "At risk is the health and safety of people, of everybody who lives in the region.
        </text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Krasnodar</name>
                <start>1</start>
                <end>10</end>
                <lat>45.06</lat>
                <lon>38.96</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Krasnodar</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Russia</name>
                <start>12</start>
                <end>18</end>
                <lat>60</lat>
                <lon>90</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Temryuk</name>
                <start>375</start>
                <end>382</end>
                <lat>45.26</lat>
                <lon>37.38</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Temryuk</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Anapa</name>
                <start>387</start>
                <end>392</end>
                <lat>44.88</lat>
                <lon>37.31</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anapa</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Krasnodar</name>
                <start>261</start>
                <end>270</end>
                <lat>45.06</lat>
                <lon>38.96</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Krasnodar</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Taiwan_culls_18000_chickens_due_to_H5N2_virus_outbreak</source>
        <text>
New outbreaks of H5N2 have been confirmed in Taiwan. Lujhu is a rural township in northwestern Taoyuan. It is located at kilometer 49 of the Highway no.1, close to the Taiwan Taoyuan International Airport (IATA: TPE). Kaohsiung is a county in southern Taiwan administered as a County of Taiwan. Mr Huang Kwo-ching, deputy director of the Bureau of Animal and Plant Health Inspection and Quarantine, however, said, "we took the most stringent measures in dealing with the episode as according to the rules of the World Organisation for Animal Health (OIE), there was no need to slaughter those chickens."</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Taiwan</name>
                <start>46</start>
                <end>52</end>
                <lat>25.03</lat>
                <lon>121.63</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taiwan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Lujhu</name>
                <start>54</start>
                <end>59</end>
                <lat>25.03</lat>
                <lon>121.28</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luzhu_District,_Taoyuan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Taoyuan</name>
                <start>96</start>
                <end>103</end>
                <lat>24.98</lat>
                <lon>121.31</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taoyuan_District</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Kaohsiung</name>
                <start>219</start>
                <end>228</end>
                <lat>22.63</lat>
                <lon>120.26</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kaohsiung</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Taiwan</name>
                <start>253</start>
                <end>259</end>
                <lat>25.03</lat>
                <lon>121.63</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taiwan</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Wild_Canadian_Goose_tests_positive_for_H5N1_in_England</source>
        <text>The H5N1 Avian Flu virus has been found in a dead wild Canadian Goose in Abbotsbury Swannery in Dorset, England. This is the eleventh case of the virus turning up in wild birds. The goose was discovered on February 25, 2008. "The finding of more cases in wild birds is not unexpected ... We are currently considering whether any additional restrictions are necessary in the area," said the United Kingdom's Health Ministry in a statement to the media. As a result of the finding, poultry movement has now been restricted by the Department for the Environment, Food and Rural Affairs (DEFRA) in the areas surrounding the Swannery. The removal of all birds, dead or alive from any property now requires a license. DEFRA says the restrictions will expire no earlier than 31 days.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Dorset</name>
                <start>97</start>
                <end>103</end>
                <lat>50.83</lat>
                <lon>-2.33</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dorset</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>England</name>
                <start>105</start>
                <end>112</end>
                <lat>51.5</lat>
                <lon>-0.11</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/England</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>United Kingdom</name>
                <start>391</start>
                <end>405</end>
                <lat>55</lat>
                <lon>-3</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Kingdom</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/%22Low_pathogenic%22_H5N1_Bird_Flu_virus_found_in_wild_ducks_in_Maryland_and_Pennsylvania</source>
        <text>The United States Department of Agriculture has announced that a "low pathogenic" form of the H5N1 Avian Flu has been found in fecal samples taken from wild Mallard ducks located in Queen Anne's County in Maryland and in Crawford County located in Pennsylvania. Officials stress that the strain is of no risk to humans. Samples from the ducks in Pennsylvania were taken on August 28. "Testing has ruled out the possibility of this being the highly pathogenic H5N1 strain that has spread through birds in Asia, Europe and Africa. Test results thus far indicate this is low pathogenic avian influenza, which poses no risk to human health. The fecal samples were collected on August 2 from resident wild ducks in Queen Anne's County, Maryland, as part of a research project conducted by Ohio State University. The fecal samples came from mallards that showed no signs of sickness," said the USDA in a statement on its website. Ducks in Pennsylvania also had shown no signs of being sick.
        </text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Queen Anne's County</name>
                <start>183</start>
                <end>202</end>
                <lat>39.03</lat>
                <lon>-76.08</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Queen_Anne%27s_County,_Maryland</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Crawford County</name>
                <start>222</start>
                <end>237</end>
                <lat>41.68</lat>
                <lon>-80.11</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crawford_County,_Pennsylvania</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Pennsylvania</name>
                <start>249</start>
                <end>261</end>
                <lat>41</lat>
                <lon>-77.5</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pennsylvania</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Pennsylvania</name>
                <start>347</start>
                <end>359</end>
                <lat>41</lat>
                <lon>-77.5</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pennsylvania</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Queen Anne's County</name>
                <start>711</start>
                <end>730</end>
                <lat>39.03</lat>
                <lon>-76.08</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Queen_Anne%27s_County,_Maryland</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Maryland</name>
                <start>732</start>
                <end>740</end>
                <lat>39</lat>
                <lon>-76.7</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maryland</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Pennsylvania</name>
                <start>934</start>
                <end>946</end>
                <lat>41</lat>
                <lon>-77.5</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pennsylvania</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Avian_flu_found_in_eastern_Canada</source>
        <text>Canada's Broadcasting Corporation reports that a case of avian flu has been discovered in a bird in the Eastern province of Prince Edward Island. The case was discovered in a gosling found in the community of O'Leary and confirmed at the Atlantic Veterinary College in Charlottetown. The announcement was made in a press release issued by the government of Prince Edward Island. Chief Health Officer for PEI, Dr. Lamont Sweet, said, "From the information we have received, there is a low risk of human illness at the present time." He went on to suggest that people in West Prince who have contact with domestic or wild birds who may be experiencing flu-like symptoms should consult their physician.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Canada</name>
                <start>1</start>
                <end>7</end>
                <lat>60</lat>
                <lon>-95</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canada</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Prince Edward Island</name>
                <start>125</start>
                <end>145</end>
                <lat>46.25</lat>
                <lon>-63</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prince_Edward_Island</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Charlottetown</name>
                <start>270</start>
                <end>283</end>
                <lat>46.23</lat>
                <lon>-63.12</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlottetown</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Prince Edward Island</name>
                <start>358</start>
                <end>378</end>
                <lat>46.25</lat>
                <lon>-63</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prince_Edward_Island</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/%22Aggressive%22_Bird_Flu_found_in_Sweden</source>
        <text>An "aggressive" strain of Avian Flu has been detected in two tufted ducks in Oskarshamn, southeast Sweden. This makes Sweden the ninth country in the EU to confirm Avian Flu on their soil. Some 35–40 wild birds were found dead. The birds were brought to Uppsala, where an analysis confirmed the presence of an "aggressive" form of Avian Flu. Tests at a laboratory in the UK will later eventually confirm whether the birds died of the lethal H5N1. Sweden's Minister of Agriculture, Ann-Christin Nykvist, said at a press conference the discovery was "serious but not unexpected." Sweden has been on high alert since the virus was found on the German island Rügen in the Baltic Sea.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Oskarshamn</name>
                <start>78</start>
                <end>88</end>
                <lat>57.26</lat>
                <lon>16.45</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oskarshamn</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Sweden</name>
                <start>100</start>
                <end>106</end>
                <lat>63</lat>
                <lon>16</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sweden</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Uppsala</name>
                <start>255</start>
                <end>262</end>
                <lat>59.85</lat>
                <lon>17.64</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uppsala</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>UK</name>
                <start>372</start>
                <end>374</end>
                <lat>55</lat>
                <lon>-3</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Kingdom</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Rügen</name>
                <start>656</start>
                <end>661</end>
                <lat>54.41</lat>
                <lon>13.4</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/R%C3%BCgen</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Baltic Sea</name>
                <start>669</start>
                <end>679</end>
                <lat>58</lat>
                <lon>20</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baltic_Sea</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Avian_Flu_is_confirmed_in_Egypt</source>
        <text>Yesterday February 17, 2006, the World Health Organisation officially declared presence of the H5N1 strain of the avian flu virus in Egypt. "There is avian flu now in Egypt," Hassan el Bushra, regional adviser for emerging diseases at the eastern Mediterranean regional office of the WHO said. His response was to the reported presence of H5N1 virus in dead birds in three areas in Egypt - namely Cairo, Giza, and Al-Minya. Today February 18, 2006, a responsible source from Egyptian ministry of health announced reporting of another 25 cases of infected birds in Al-Minya with aftermath of 35 confirmed cases between birds, yet there are no human cases reported.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Egypt</name>
                <start>134</start>
                <end>139</end>
                <lat>26</lat>
                <lon>30</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Egypt</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Mediterranean</name>
                <start>248</start>
                <end>261</end>
                <lat>35</lat>
                <lon>18</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mediterranean_Sea</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Cairo</name>
                <start>398</start>
                <end>403</end>
                <lat>30.04</lat>
                <lon>31.23</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cairo</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Giza</name>
                <start>405</start>
                <end>409</end>
                <lat>30.01</lat>
                <lon>31.21</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Giza</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Al-Minya</name>
                <start>415</start>
                <end>423</end>
                <lat>28.11</lat>
                <lon>30.74</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minya,_Egypt</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Bird_Flu_confirmed_in_1,000_UK_turkeys</source>
        <text>1,000 turkeys in the United Kingdom have been confirmed by UK government officials as dying of a strain of avian flu and a further 1,600 have died since the infection was initially reported. The birds, believed to be from a Bernard Matthews owned farm in Suffolk fell ill and died this week after contracting the H5 strain of the flu. It is likely that all other poultry on the farm will be culled. The department were swift in carrying out a full investigation and sent samples to be tested at facilities in Weybridge. This report comes less than a year after a mass culling of 50,000 birds in Norfolk after an outbreak of the H7 strain.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>United Kingdom</name>
                <start>22</start>
                <end>36</end>
                <lat>55</lat>
                <lon>-3</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Kingdom</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Suffolk</name>
                <start>256</start>
                <end>263</end>
                <lat>52.16</lat>
                <lon>1</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suffolk</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Norfolk</name>
                <start>596</start>
                <end>603</end>
                <lat>52.66</lat>
                <lon>1</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Norfolk</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Weybridge</name>
                <start>510</start>
                <end>519</end>
                <lat>51.36</lat>
                <lon>-0.45</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Weybridge</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Bird_Flu_kills_40th_Indonesian</source>
        <text>The World Health Organisation confirmed the death of a five-year-old boy on June 16 was due to bird flu. This is the 40th confirmed Indonesian death due to bird flu. The boy died in Tulungagung, East Java province, after being admitted to hospital on June 8. There was a dead chicken 15 metres from his home. The death was confirmed by a WHO laboratory in Hong Kong. Deaths due to bird flu have steadily risen since its outbreak in Indonesia in 2003. This year they have recorded the highest death toll in the world.
        </text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Tulungagung</name>
                <start>183</start>
                <end>194</end>
                <lat>-8.06</lat>
                <lon>111.9</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tulungagung_Regency</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>East Java</name>
                <start>196</start>
                <end>205</end>
                <lat>-7.26</lat>
                <lon>112.75</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/East_Java</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Hong Kong</name>
                <start>357</start>
                <end>366</end>
                <lat>22.3</lat>
                <lon>114.2</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hong_Kong</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Indonesia</name>
                <start>433</start>
                <end>442</end>
                <lat>-5</lat>
                <lon>120</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indonesia</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Bird_flu_spreading_through_Indonesia_and_China</source>
        <text>Two Indonesian women, 23 and 27, have tested positive for the H5N1 strain of avian influenza. They are in "serious condition but seem to be improving," said Hariadi Wibisono, a senior health ministry official. They are being treated in the designated bird flu hospital, Sulianti Suroso in eastern Jakarta. It is believed that both women had contact with infected poultry. This brings Indonesia's number of confirmed cases of the virus to 25. A 26 year old female farmer in Fujian, China whose surname is Lin, also has the deadly H5N1 virus. She was admitted to the hospital in January, but it was only confirmed on Wednesday that she had the virus. Some of the people that have come in close contact with the woman are under observation by local health officials. Her current condition is reported as stable. This is China's eleventh confirmed case of the virus.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Jakarta</name>
                <start>298</start>
                <end>305</end>
                <lat>-6.2</lat>
                <lon>106.81</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jakarta</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Indonesia</name>
                <start>385</start>
                <end>394</end>
                <lat>-5</lat>
                <lon>120</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indonesia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Fujian</name>
                <start>474</start>
                <end>480</end>
                <lat>25.9</lat>
                <lon>118.3</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fujian</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>China</name>
                <start>482</start>
                <end>487</end>
                <lat>35</lat>
                <lon>103</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/China</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>China</name>
                <start>818</start>
                <end>823</end>
                <lat>35</lat>
                <lon>103</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/China</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/British_report_says_the_U.K._is_preparing_%27mass_graves%27_for_humans_if_Bird_Flu_mutates</source>
        <text>"Prudent precautionary planning is under way across all elements of the response, including the health service, other essential services and local authorities," said a Home Office spokesman. However; at the moment, the virus only infects humans who have been in close or direct contact with infected poultry. The U.K. also reports that it has stockpiled at least 14.6 million doses of anti-viral medication. The report cautions that vaccines against the virus "will not be available in the first wave of a pandemic" and that the vaccines would not be a "silver bullet." It also states that the local officials are prepared to handle only 48,000 deaths in Wales and in England for a pandemic lasting 15 weeks, however; the reports states further that, "even with ramping local management capacity by 100%, the prudent worst case of 320,000 deaths is projected to lead to a delay of some 17 weeks from death to burial or cremation."</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>U.K.</name>
                <start>314</start>
                <end>318</end>
                <lat>55</lat>
                <lon>-3</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Kingdom</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Wales</name>
                <start>656</start>
                <end>661</end>
                <lat>52.3</lat>
                <lon>-3.6</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wales</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>England</name>
                <start>669</start>
                <end>676</end>
                <lat>51.5</lat>
                <lon>-0.11</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/England</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Chickens_at_a_Norfolk_farm_to_be_culled_after_testing_positive_for_bird_flu</source>
        <text>35,000 chickens at Witford Lodge Farm at Norfolk, England are to be culled after some chickens found dead tested positive for bird flu. Further tests are being carried out to establish which strain of the virus it was, but preliminary results suggest it is not the H5N1 strain, but is instead the H7N7 strain. The birds are being culled as a precautionary measure. The H7N7 strain can be transmitted to humans, but not as easily or as lethally as the H5N1 strain. Previous outbreaks of the H7N7 strain include one from 2003 in the Netherlands, which infected more than 80 people and led to the death of one vet. So far the only positive test for H5N1 in the UK has been a dead swan found in Fife.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Norfolk</name>
                <start>42</start>
                <end>49</end>
                <lat>52.66</lat>
                <lon>1</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Norfolk</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>England</name>
                <start>51</start>
                <end>58</end>
                <lat>51.5</lat>
                <lon>-0.11</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/England</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Netherlands</name>
                <start>532</start>
                <end>543</end>
                <lat>52.31</lat>
                <lon>5.55</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Netherlands</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>UK</name>
                <start>659</start>
                <end>661</end>
                <lat>55</lat>
                <lon>-3</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Kingdom</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Fife</name>
                <start>692</start>
                <end>696</end>
                <lat>56.25</lat>
                <lon>-3.2</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fife</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/China_and_Europe_face_new_avian_flu_outbreaks</source>
        <text>
China has announced a new outbreak of avian flu today along with similar cases in Russia, Romania, and Macedonia. China's news agency reported that 2,600 birds have died of the H5N1 strain in northern China, declaring that the outbreak was found in a breeding facility in Hohhot, the capital of Inner Mongolia. The government maintains the epidemic is under control. Russia is waiting for confirmation that it was the H5N1 strain that killed several hundred ducks near Moscow; if the tests return positive it will be a major spread of the virus across the Ural Mountains, into European Russia. A small village in southern Macedonia also suspects the strain. Plans are already made to kill 10,000 birds to contain the outbreak. Romania confirmed that there has been another outbreak in the Danube Delta area. The strain was confirmed there last weekend, whereupon 4,500 birds were destroyed. H5N1 is the strain scientists fear could be transmitted from human to human, causing a flu pandemic. So far 50 people have died of it, all having worked closely with birds. It is not easy to pass the disease from bird to human.
        </text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>China</name>
                <start>1</start>
                <end>6</end>
                <lat>35</lat>
                <lon>103</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/China</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Russia</name>
                <start>83</start>
                <end>89</end>
                <lat>60</lat>
                <lon>90</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Romania</name>
                <start>91</start>
                <end>98</end>
                <lat>46</lat>
                <lon>25</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Romania</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Macedonia</name>
                <start>104</start>
                <end>113</end>
                <lat>41.6</lat>
                <lon>21.7</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Republic_of_Macedonia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>China</name>
                <start>202</start>
                <end>207</end>
                <lat>35</lat>
                <lon>103</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/China</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Hohhot</name>
                <start>273</start>
                <end>279</end>
                <lat>40.81</lat>
                <lon>111.65</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hohhot</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Inner Mongolia</name>
                <start>296</start>
                <end>310</end>
                <lat>44</lat>
                <lon>113</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inner_Mongolia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Moscow</name>
                <start>470</start>
                <end>476</end>
                <lat>55.75</lat>
                <lon>37.61</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moscow</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Danube Delta</name>
                <start>790</start>
                <end>802</end>
                <lat>45.33</lat>
                <lon>29.5</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Danube_Delta</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Duck_hunters_asked_to_help_monitor_spread_of_Avian_Flu</source>
        <text>Virginia duck and goose hunters, and waterfowl hunters in other parts of the US, might for the first time find themselves approached by state game officials who are testing harvested birds for the presence of Avian Flu. The migratory flyways considered most at risk of disease transmission are on the Pacific side of the Americas in Alaska and the Pacific NorthWest, closest to Asia. The Atlantic flyway shares migratory influence from Europe and Africa where the Avian Flu has also been found. A low pathogenic strain of H5N1 that currently exists in North America is common among waterfowl. Testing for the more virulent strains involves swabbing the bird's throat or rectum.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Virginia</name>
                <start>1</start>
                <end>9</end>
                <lat>37.5</lat>
                <lon>-79</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virginia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>US</name>
                <start>78</start>
                <end>80</end>
                <lat>40</lat>
                <lon>-100</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Alaska</name>
                <start>334</start>
                <end>340</end>
                <lat>64</lat>
                <lon>-150</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alaska</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Europe_restricts_poultry_as_bird_flu_spreads_to_eight_European_nations</source>
        <text>Authorities across Europe have issued restrictions on commercial poultry farms, following the outbreak of bird flu in eight previously unaffected nations. The virus has been found in migratory birds much earlier than had been expected. Tests have confirmed that wild swans in Greece, Bulgaria, Italy, Austria and Germany had died from the deadly H5N1 strain of the virus. Other suspected cases of the virus have been detected in Slovenia, Croatia and Denmark. European health officials had expected wild birds migrating from Africa to Europe in spring to carry the disease into Western Europe. It is thought that swans were migrating from Russia and Ukraine to the Black Sea driven by unusually cold weather. Globally, 91 people have died after contracting the virus from close contact with diseased birds, but the greatest concern for European authorities is that an outbreak will occur among domesticated fowl, destroying local poultry industries. The H5N1 strain of bird flu is highly contagious, and lethal to birds. A single outbreak can kill tens of thousands of birds, and all birds must be culled across a wide region to prevent the spread of the disease.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Greece</name>
                <start>277</start>
                <end>283</end>
                <lat>39</lat>
                <lon>22</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greece</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Bulgaria</name>
                <start>285</start>
                <end>293</end>
                <lat>42.75</lat>
                <lon>25.5</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bulgaria</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Italy</name>
                <start>295</start>
                <end>300</end>
                <lat>43</lat>
                <lon>12</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Italy</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Austria</name>
                <start>302</start>
                <end>309</end>
                <lat>47.33</lat>
                <lon>13.33</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Austria</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Germany</name>
                <start>314</start>
                <end>321</end>
                <lat>51</lat>
                <lon>9</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Germany</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Slovenia</name>
                <start>430</start>
                <end>438</end>
                <lat>46.11</lat>
                <lon>14.81</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slovenia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Croatia</name>
                <start>440</start>
                <end>447</end>
                <lat>45.16</lat>
                <lon>15.5</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Croatia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Denmark</name>
                <start>452</start>
                <end>459</end>
                <lat>56</lat>
                <lon>10</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Denmark</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Egyptian_woman_becomes_third_to_die_of_bird_flu_in_a_week</source>
        <text>A woman in Egypt has died of the H5N1 strain of bird flu. H5N1 has killed two other Egyptian women already this week, bringing the total dead of the virus in Egypt to 18. Fardous Mahammed Hadad was taken into hospital on Sunday after having difficulty breathing and developing a high fever, and subsequently tested positive for bird flu. She died today, at the age of 36. As well as Hadad, who was from Menoufia, this week saw the deaths of Fatima Fathi Mohammed from Daqahliya and Ola Youness Mohammed from Beni Suef. They all died from H5N1; Ola Youness Mohammed's case was Egypt's first since July. In addition, the World Health Organisation says two further woman are infected without giving any further details; the United Nations health agency says that on December 24 a 50-year-old woman was hospitalised and remains in critical condition, whilst a chicken seller, 22, is recovering from the infection in intensive care.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Egypt</name>
                <start>12</start>
                <end>17</end>
                <lat>26</lat>
                <lon>30</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Egypt</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Egypt</name>
                <start>159</start>
                <end>164</end>
                <lat>26</lat>
                <lon>30</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Egypt</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Menoufia</name>
                <start>404</start>
                <end>412</end>
                <lat>30.52</lat>
                <lon>30.99</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monufia_Governorate</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Daqahliya</name>
                <start>469</start>
                <end>478</end>
                <lat>31.05</lat>
                <lon>31.38</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dakahlia_Governorate</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Beni Suef</name>
                <start>509</start>
                <end>518</end>
                <lat>29.06</lat>
                <lon>31.08</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beni_Suef</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Egypt</name>
                <start>577</start>
                <end>582</end>
                <lat>26</lat>
                <lon>30</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Egypt</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/First_bird_flu_case_reported_in_North_Korea</source>
        <text>
North Korea's official news agency, KCNA, reported an outbreak of bird flu in the capital of Pyongyang. KCNA reported three separate outbreaks at poultry farms in the capital, and said hundreds of thousands of chickens have been culled in an attempt to stop the spread of the disease. Radio Pyongyang said, "countermeasures are underway to prevent an epidemic and stem the spread to other poultry farms". Experts warned that a bird flu epidemic in North Korea would deprive the population of its main source of protein.
        </text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>North Korea</name>
                <start>1</start>
                <end>12</end>
                <lat>40</lat>
                <lon>127</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/North_Korea</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Pyongyang</name>
                <start>94</start>
                <end>103</end>
                <lat>39.01</lat>
                <lon>125.73</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pyongyang</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>North Korea</name>
                <start>449</start>
                <end>460</end>
                <lat>40</lat>
                <lon>127</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/North_Korea</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/First_bird_flu_cases_registered_In_Maharashtra,_India</source>
        <text>The first cases of bird flu have been registered in the world's second most populous country, India. The cases registered are reportedly from the Nandurbar Slaughter House in the western state of Maharashtra. Some 1500 birds have been reported as having the disease. Maharashtra Animal Husbandary Minister Anees Ahmed confirmed the reports and said that effective steps will be taken with the help of eminent veterinarians. Ahmed also said a high-level meeting was under way in Mumbai to assess the situation and to decide how to cull the large flocks of birds in poultries in Nandurbar and Dhule districts.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>India</name>
                <start>95</start>
                <end>100</end>
                <lat>21</lat>
                <lon>78</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/India</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Maharashtra</name>
                <start>197</start>
                <end>208</end>
                <lat>18.97</lat>
                <lon>72.82</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maharashtra</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Mumbai</name>
                <start>479</start>
                <end>485</end>
                <lat>18.97</lat>
                <lon>72.82</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mumbai</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Nandurbar</name>
                <start>578</start>
                <end>587</end>
                <lat>21.37</lat>
                <lon>74.25</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nandurbar</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Dhule</name>
                <start>592</start>
                <end>597</end>
                <lat>20.89</lat>
                <lon>74.76</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dhule</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/First_Iraqi_case_of_Avian_Flu_reported</source>
        <text>The first case of Avian Flu in Iraq was announced today by the country's Health Minister, Abdel Mutalib Mohammed. The preliminary result was reportedly from a United States military laboratory in Cairo; the World Health Organisation are expected to seek confirmation of this from a UK laboratory. The victim was Shangen Abdul Qader, a 15-year-old girl from the northern Kurdish village of Ranya. Her suspected H5N1 infection killed her on January 17. The death of the girl's uncle is also believed to be under investigation due to him having symptoms that may indicate flu. The area of Iraq where the suspected deaths occurred borders Turkey where there have been 12 confirmed cases of which four resulted in death. Turkey's last reported victim, Fatma Ozcan, was also aged 15.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Iraq</name>
                <start>32</start>
                <end>36</end>
                <lat>33</lat>
                <lon>44</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iraq</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>United States</name>
                <start>160</start>
                <end>173</end>
                <lat>40</lat>
                <lon>-100</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Cairo</name>
                <start>197</start>
                <end>202</end>
                <lat>30.04</lat>
                <lon>31.23</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cairo</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>UK</name>
                <start>283</start>
                <end>285</end>
                <lat>55</lat>
                <lon>-3</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Kingdom</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Ranya</name>
                <start>390</start>
                <end>395</end>
                <lat>36.25</lat>
                <lon>44.88</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ranya</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Turkey</name>
                <start>636</start>
                <end>642</end>
                <lat>39</lat>
                <lon>35</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turkey</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Turkey</name>
                <start>717</start>
                <end>723</end>
                <lat>39</lat>
                <lon>35</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turkey</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/H5N1_bird_flu_confirmed_in_the_Netherlands</source>
        <text>The Dutch government has confirmed its first H5N1 bird flu case in the country. The case was found in 2 dead young owls in a zoo in Rotterdam. A lab in Lelystad confirmed that the bird flu was first discovered after a routine test by the Wild Life Health Centre and found traces of H5N1. Further tests will be carried out due to be released in a few days. Netherlands has never had a reported case of H5N1 before. As bird flu can only spread by close contact, the zoo will remain open, but restrictions will be in place to protect visitors, staff and other animals. The source of the bird flu is unknown. Staff have been given prophylactic medication.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Rotterdam</name>
                <start>133</start>
                <end>142</end>
                <lat>51.91</lat>
                <lon>4.5</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rotterdam</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Lelystad</name>
                <start>153</start>
                <end>161</end>
                <lat>52.5</lat>
                <lon>5.48</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lelystad</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Netherlands</name>
                <start>357</start>
                <end>368</end>
                <lat>52.31</lat>
                <lon>5.55</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Netherlands</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/H5N1_bird_flu_virus_reaches_Poland</source>
        <text>The two cases in Poland were discovered in the northern town of Toruń, famous as the birthplace of Nicolaus Copernicus. Two swans have been confirmed to have been carriers of the virus. Samples from the subjects have been sent to the European Union (EU) laboratories in Weybridge, England, but initial assessments have been seen as highly reliable. "Yes, we have confirmed that it is definitely H5N1," said Jan Zmudzinski, director of Poland's national laboratory, in the town of Pulawy. A hygiene-security zone protected by police has been established, extending up to several hundred metres from the spot on the river bank of the Vistula river where the swans were found. Boud, a resident of Toruń, told Wikinews that he has observed authorities putting precautionary measures in place to attempt to slow the spread of bird flu.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Poland</name>
                <start>18</start>
                <end>24</end>
                <lat>52</lat>
                <lon>20</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poland</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Toruń</name>
                <start>65</start>
                <end>70</end>
                <lat>53.03</lat>
                <lon>18.61</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toru%C5%84</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Weybridge</name>
                <start>271</start>
                <end>280</end>
                <lat>51.36</lat>
                <lon>-0.45</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Weybridge</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>England</name>
                <start>282</start>
                <end>289</end>
                <lat>51.5</lat>
                <lon>-0.11</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/England</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Pulawy</name>
                <start>481</start>
                <end>487</end>
                <lat>51.41</lat>
                <lon>21.96</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pu%C5%82awy</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Toruń</name>
                <start>695</start>
                <end>700</end>
                <lat>53.03</lat>
                <lon>18.61</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toru%C5%84</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/H5N1_confirmed_in_France</source>
        <text>The strain of bird flu lethal to humans, H5N1, has been confirmed to have infected a dead wild duck, found on Monday, in marshland near Lyon in the east of France. France is the seventh country in the European Union to suffer this virus; following Austria, Germany, Slovenia, Bulgaria, Greece and Italy. Suspected cases of H5N1 in Croatia and Denmark remain unconfirmed. Globally, The H5N1 strain has infected 171 people, and killed 93 of them, since 2003. France, as the largest producer of poultry in Europe, already has farmers worrying about their livelihood; despite the fact the avian flu has not affected any of the nation's poultry. If the disease transfers to poultry, the transport of poultry can be restricted. Further tests have been done on two ducks that have died in the Somme region in the north of France.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Lyon</name>
                <start>137</start>
                <end>141</end>
                <lat>45.76</lat>
                <lon>4.84</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lyon</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>France</name>
                <start>157</start>
                <end>163</end>
                <lat>47</lat>
                <lon>2</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/France</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>France</name>
                <start>165</start>
                <end>171</end>
                <lat>47</lat>
                <lon>2</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/France</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Austria</name>
                <start>249</start>
                <end>256</end>
                <lat>47.33</lat>
                <lon>13.33</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Austria</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Germany</name>
                <start>258</start>
                <end>265</end>
                <lat>51</lat>
                <lon>9</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Germany</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Slovenia</name>
                <start>267</start>
                <end>275</end>
                <lat>46.11</lat>
                <lon>14.81</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slovenia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Greece</name>
                <start>287</start>
                <end>293</end>
                <lat>39</lat>
                <lon>22</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greece</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Italy</name>
                <start>298</start>
                <end>303</end>
                <lat>43</lat>
                <lon>12</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Italy</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Croatia</name>
                <start>332</start>
                <end>339</end>
                <lat>45.16</lat>
                <lon>15.5</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Croatia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Denmark</name>
                <start>344</start>
                <end>351</end>
                <lat>56</lat>
                <lon>10</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Denmark</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Somme</name>
                <start>787</start>
                <end>792</end>
                <lat>49.91</lat>
                <lon>2.5</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Somme</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/H5N1_strain_of_Avian_Flu_found_in_the_UK</source>
        <text>Health officials in the United Kingdom have confirmed that the H5N1 strain of the Avian Flu has been found in turkeys on Redgrave Park Farm in Suffolk, England. The farm is owned by Gressingham Foods. Officials also say that the commission for the European Union have been notified. In April of 2006, the deadly H5N1 virus was found in the remains of a wild Mute Swan in the village of Cellardyke in Fife, Scotland. In February, poultry producer Bernard Matthews' farm in Suffolk had more than 160,000 birds killed after they were infected with the H5N1 virus.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>United Kingdom</name>
                <start>25</start>
                <end>39</end>
                <lat>55</lat>
                <lon>-3</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Kingdom</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Suffolk</name>
                <start>144</start>
                <end>151</end>
                <lat>52.16</lat>
                <lon>1</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suffolk</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>England</name>
                <start>153</start>
                <end>160</end>
                <lat>51.5</lat>
                <lon>-0.11</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/England</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Cellardyke</name>
                <start>387</start>
                <end>397</end>
                <lat>56.21</lat>
                <lon>-2.7</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cellardyke</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Fife</name>
                <start>401</start>
                <end>405</end>
                <lat>56.25</lat>
                <lon>-3.2</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fife</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Scotland</name>
                <start>407</start>
                <end>415</end>
                <lat>56</lat>
                <lon>-4</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scotland</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Suffolk</name>
                <start>473</start>
                <end>480</end>
                <lat>52.16</lat>
                <lon>1</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suffolk</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Indonesian_Health_Ministry:_Two_new_human_clusters_of_Bird_Flu_suspected_in_Sumatra</source>
        <text>The Indonesian Health Ministry has stated that at least seven people, including three children from northern Sumatra province in the district of Karo, are being hospitalized with suspected H5N1 Bird Flu and officials believe that the infected are part of "two clusters" of family members who are sick. The individuals are being treated at Adam Malik Hospital located in Medan. All individuals were admitted on Tuesday. The Associated Press quoted Nyoman Kandun, a Health Ministry official, as saying, "there are two clusters, one with two sisters, the other with three family members, and another two of their neighbours." The three children range in age from 18 months to six-years-old. However; experts are waiting on results from tests on the individuals and must be "scientifically proven," said Runizar Ruesin, also a Health Ministry official. The condition of all victims are stable, however; all victims have a fever, a cough, and flu-like symptoms which officials say resemble the symptoms of Bird Flu.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Sumatra</name>
                <start>110</start>
                <end>117</end>
                <lat>0</lat>
                <lon>102</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sumatra</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Karo</name>
                <start>146</start>
                <end>150</end>
                <lat>3.1</lat>
                <lon>98.5</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karo_Regency</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Medan</name>
                <start>371</start>
                <end>376</end>
                <lat>3.58</lat>
                <lon>98.66</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Medan</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Mass_poultry_vaccination_planned_by_China</source>
        <text>Millions of infected birds have been slaughtered in China and despite the spread of the virus it is only today that the World Health Organization has confirmed the first human cases in the country. The cases include at least one fatality, a 24-year-old female poultry worker in the eastern province of Anhui. The other confirmed case is a 9-year-old boy in the central province of Hunan who has since recovered. The officials in Liaoning have reportedly finished vaccinating all 320 million birds in the northeastern province. David Nabarro, the United Nations coordinator for bird and human flu, says such vaccination programs are "the right thing to do" since slaughtering the animals will not work due to the virus being so entrenched in China's birds.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>China</name>
                <start>53</start>
                <end>58</end>
                <lat>35</lat>
                <lon>103</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/China</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Anhui</name>
                <start>303</start>
                <end>308</end>
                <lat>31.83</lat>
                <lon>117</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anhui</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Hunan</name>
                <start>382</start>
                <end>387</end>
                <lat>27.4</lat>
                <lon>111.8</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hunan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Liaoning</name>
                <start>430</start>
                <end>438</end>
                <lat>41.1</lat>
                <lon>122.3</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liaoning</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>China</name>
                <start>742</start>
                <end>747</end>
                <lat>35</lat>
                <lon>103</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/China</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/New_avian_flu_outbreaks_reported_in_western_Europe</source>
        <text>At least 38 new cases of the H5N1 strain of bird flu have been found in wild birds in eastern Germany today. These discoveries, in conjunction with the fifth outbreak in France in 17 months, have prompted both countries to raise the bird flu risk assessment level. German scientists discovered the outbreak after receiving 38 confirmed cases, all of which came from the eastern states of Saxony-Anhalt and Thuringia. In France, three swans have been found dead in an Assenoncourt pond sparking a massive response from French authorities. Careful monitoring will take place for any further deaths or signs of illness in this area. Many commercial poultry owners have been told to keep their birds inside as a precaution to prevent the disease from spreading further through Europe. French health minister Roselyn Bachelot has stated that the current state of alert is appropriate, given the potential risk to human life posed by influenza.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Germany</name>
                <start>95</start>
                <end>102</end>
                <lat>51</lat>
                <lon>9</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Germany</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>France</name>
                <start>171</start>
                <end>177</end>
                <lat>47</lat>
                <lon>2</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/France</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Saxony-Anhalt</name>
                <start>389</start>
                <end>402</end>
                <lat>51.97</lat>
                <lon>11.47</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saxony-Anhalt</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Thuringia</name>
                <start>407</start>
                <end>416</end>
                <lat>50.86</lat>
                <lon>11.05</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thuringia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Assenoncourt</name>
                <start>468</start>
                <end>480</end>
                <lat>48.77</lat>
                <lon>6.79</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Assenoncourt</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/New_bird_flu_outbreaks_reported_in_Europe</source>
        <text>Cases of the H5 type of the avian flu have been discovered in Romanian and Ukrainian fowl. Romania has banned hunting in parts of the country and Ukrainian troops have moved from house to house in villages rounding up chickens, ducks and geese for a mass cull. The village of Ciocile in the Romanian county of Brăila has been quarantined and thousands of birds have been killed in an attempt to contain the outbreak, the Bucharest Daily News reported. The H5 virus had been detected in nearby villages of Bumbacari and Dudescu in previous tests on Thursday. Romanian Agriculture Minister Gheorghe Flutur said that further tests in a British laboratory will be needed to determine whether the outbreak is the lethal H5N1 strain, which is feared to be able to mutate into a form that would be easily transmitted between humans. The H5N1 strain has already been confirmed in the villages of Ceamurlia de Jos, Maliuc and Caraorman, where the virus is suspected to have been brought by birds from Russia. The large delta area is a destination for migrating fowl. Meanwhile, five Ukrainian villages in Crimea have been the site for a mass cull in order to contain the country's first bird flu outbreak. Though tough measures are being taken in the area, villagers say their poultry had been infected by the disease for more than two months without any official action being taken.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Romania</name>
                <start>92</start>
                <end>99</end>
                <lat>46</lat>
                <lon>25</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Romania</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Ciocile</name>
                <start>277</start>
                <end>284</end>
                <lat>44.81</lat>
                <lon>27.23</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ciocile</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Brăila</name>
                <start>311</start>
                <end>317</end>
                <lat>45.11</lat>
                <lon>27.68</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Br%C4%83ila_County</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Bumbacari</name>
                <start>506</start>
                <end>515</end>
                <lat>44.88</lat>
                <lon>27.44</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dude%C8%99ti,_Br%C4%83ila</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Dudescu</name>
                <start>520</start>
                <end>527</end>
                <lat>44.88</lat>
                <lon>27.44</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dude%C8%99ti,_Br%C4%83ila</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Ceamurlia de Jos</name>
                <start>889</start>
                <end>905</end>
                <lat>44.73</lat>
                <lon>28.71</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ceamurlia_de_Jos</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Maliuc</name>
                <start>907</start>
                <end>913</end>
                <lat>45.16</lat>
                <lon>29.08</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maliuc</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Caraorman</name>
                <start>918</start>
                <end>927</end>
                <lat>45.1</lat>
                <lon>29.3</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cri%C8%99an,_Tulcea</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Russia</name>
                <start>993</start>
                <end>999</end>
                <lat>60</lat>
                <lon>90</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Crimea</name>
                <start>1097</start>
                <end>1103</end>
                <lat>45.3</lat>
                <lon>34.4</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crimea</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Suspected_low_pathogenic_H5N1_Bird_Flu_virus_found_in_the_United_States</source>
        <text>Scientists have discovered the possible presence of the H5N1 Bird Flu virus in wild mute swans in Michigan on the coast of Lake Erie near the Mouillee state game area in Monroe County. The swans were sampled on August 8, 2006 and the initial testing was done at Michigan State University's Diagnostic Center for Population and Animal Health and at the National Veterinary Services laboratories in Ames, Iowa. White House Press Secretary Tony Snow says that "They (the scientists) believe it is a strain of low pathogenicity, similar to strains that have been seen before in North America." Snow also added that "this [case] is not what we're accustomed to hearing about from Asia." "Test results thus far indicate this is low pathogenicity avian influenza, which poses no threat to human health. Routine surveillance has indicated the presence of H5 and N1 avian influenza subtypes in samples from two wild mute swans in Michigan," said a statement on the United States Department of Agriculture's (USDA) website. The statement also went on to say that the swans "did not show signs of sickness" and that the swans were infected with "two separate" strains of Avian Flu. "It is possible that these birds were not infected with an H5N1 strain, but instead with two separate avian influenza viruses, one containing H5 and the other containing N1," said the statement. "This is not the highly pathogenic avian influenza virus that has spread through much of other parts of the world. We do not believe this virus represents a risk to human health," said USDA's Animal and Plant Health inspector, Ron DeHaven. Health officials are remaining "remaining vigilant and prepared," said Department of Health and Human Services science advisor, Dr. William Raub. Further tests will be done to confirm that there is in fact a virus there and what type and are expected sometime today.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Michigan</name>
                <start>99</start>
                <end>107</end>
                <lat>44</lat>
                <lon>-85</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michigan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Lake Erie</name>
                <start>124</start>
                <end>133</end>
                <lat>42.2</lat>
                <lon>-81.2</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lake_Erie</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Mouillee</name>
                <start>143</start>
                <end>151</end>
                <lat>42</lat>
                <lon>-83.19</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pointe_Mouillee_State_Game_Area</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Monroe County</name>
                <start>171</start>
                <end>184</end>
                <lat>41.92</lat>
                <lon>-83.5</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monroe_County,_Michigan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Ames</name>
                <start>398</start>
                <end>402</end>
                <lat>42.03</lat>
                <lon>-93.62</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ames,_Iowa</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Iowa</name>
                <start>404</start>
                <end>408</end>
                <lat>42</lat>
                <lon>-93</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iowa</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Michigan</name>
                <start>922</start>
                <end>930</end>
                <lat>44</lat>
                <lon>-85</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michigan</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Swan_in_German_zoo_tests_positive_for_H5N1_virus</source>
        <text>A "highly pathogenic strain" of the H5N1 Avian Flu virus has been detected in a dead Australian black swan, floating in a pond located at the Dresden Zoo in Dresden, Germany. Conflicting reports say that the swan was found on Monday, Tuesday or Wednesday. The Friedrich Loeffler Institute which specializes in animal diseases confirmed the test results. "We can confirm that this is the highly pathogenic strain," said a spokesperson for the institute. Officials have blocked off an area of Dresden approximately 1.9 miles (3km) from the site where the swan was found and have posted observation areas at approximately 6.2 miles (10km) outside the area as a precaution. For the moment, all birds in the zoo have been confined to their cages and viewing of birds by the public is no longer permitted. The zoo still remains open for business and cleaning efforts have been intensified. Officials have also restricted cats and dogs from roaming areas nearby. There are at least 112 different species of birds, totaling 720, located at the zoo.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Dresden</name>
                <start>158</start>
                <end>165</end>
                <lat>51.03</lat>
                <lon>13.73</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dresden</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Germany</name>
                <start>167</start>
                <end>174</end>
                <lat>51</lat>
                <lon>9</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Germany</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Dresden</name>
                <start>492</start>
                <end>499</end>
                <lat>51.03</lat>
                <lon>13.73</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dresden</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Turkish_government_accused_of_being_too_slow_to_respond_to_bird_flu</source>
        <text>The Turkish government has come under fire from officials in Dogubayazit, where three siblings died from the H5N1 strain of Bird Flu, for not sending enough resources and not responding quickly enough in the region. The mayor of Dogubayazit, Mukkades Kubilay, claims that the Turkish government sent only three doctors and that there were not enough workers to destroy poultry. The government has been accused of doing too little, too late. H5N1 was discovered in Turkish poultry in December, 2005. Agriculture Minister Mehdi Eker dismissed the claim, saying that culling of infected poultry began immediately following the discovery of H5N1 on December 15, 2005. Questions about whether the government acted aggressively enough early in the outbreak emerged as officials tried to contain the disease, which Eker said had been confirmed in 11 of Turkey's 81 provinces and was suspected in 14 others. The number of confirmed human cases of H5N1 in Turkey is 18. Three of those have died from the virus.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Dogubayazit</name>
                <start>62</start>
                <end>73</end>
                <lat>39.54</lat>
                <lon>44.08</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Do%C4%9Fubeyaz%C4%B1t</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Dogubayazit</name>
                <start>230</start>
                <end>241</end>
                <lat>39.54</lat>
                <lon>44.08</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Do%C4%9Fubeyaz%C4%B1t</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Turkey</name>
                <start>847</start>
                <end>853</end>
                <lat>39</lat>
                <lon>35</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turkey</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Turkey</name>
                <start>948</start>
                <end>954</end>
                <lat>39</lat>
                <lon>35</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turkey</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Wild_ducks_in_Illinois_test_positive_for_%22low_pathogenic%22_Bird_Flu_virus</source>
        <text>The United States Department of Agriculture has announced that 5 out of 11 wild migratory Green-winged Teals have tested positive for a "low pathogenic sub type" of the H5 and N1 Avian Flu virus or Bird Flu virus, but also say that this is not the same type of Avian Flu that has killed over 150 people worldwide and that the detection poses "no threat to humans." "Initial tests confirm that these wild duck samples do not contain the highly pathogenic H5N1 strain that has spread through birds in Asia, Europe and Africa. These samples were collected from apparently healthy birds and initial test results indicate the presence of low pathogenic avian influenza (LPAI) virus, which poses no threat to human health," said the USDA in a statement on its website. Samples from the ducks were retrieved on September 24, 2006 and were found in the Rice Lake area of Fulton County located in Illinois. The USDA and the Illinois Department of Natural Resources tested the samples as part of a Bird Flu monitoring program. The USDA also says that they do not expect to find any "additional cases of common strains of avian influenza in birds." "These strains of the virus include LPAI H5N1, commonly referred to as "North American" H5N1, which is very different from the more severe HPAI H5N1 circulating overseas," said the statement. The ducks are not believed to be infected with the deadly H5N1 virus, but officials say both subtypes H5 and N1 have been found in the samples.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Rice Lake</name>
                <start>846</start>
                <end>855</end>
                <lat>40.46</lat>
                <lon>-89.92</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rice_Lake_(Illinois)</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Fulton County</name>
                <start>864</start>
                <end>877</end>
                <lat>40.48</lat>
                <lon>-90.21</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fulton_County,_Illinois</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Illinois</name>
                <start>889</start>
                <end>897</end>
                <lat>40</lat>
                <lon>-89</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Illinois</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/9_year_old_girl_reported_to_be_latest_US_swine_flu_death</source>
        <text>The latest Swine Flu death in the United States is reported to be a 9-year-old girl from Buffalo, New York. Maya Harden died from complications caused by the virus at Women and Children's Hospital on Saturday morning. She is the second Swine Flu victim to die in Buffalo in the last week. According to WIVB Channel 4, Harden who attended 4th grade at Buffalo Science Magnet School 59, had been admitted to Children's Hospital on June 16, where she remained on life support until her death. The report says that during that period, Harden was contracted pneumonia which then lead to an infection. Harden was just nine days short of celebrating her 10th birthday. At least one other child from School 59 is reported to be in critical condition at Children's Hospital. On June 20, a 15-year-old boy also from Buffalo, died at the same hospital, and developing pneumonia. He was initially suffering from renal failure. The boy, Eighth grader Matthew Davis attended class at Buffalo Science Magnet School 97. In a statement to the press, Dr. James Williams, Superintendent of Buffalo Public Schools, called the deaths a terrible loss. "It is with a heavy heart and deep sadness that I inform our Buffalo Public Schools family and the entire Buffalo community that we mourn the loss of another student. Please keep the family in your thoughts and prayers during this very difficult time while they struggle with this terrible loss." According to the World Health Organization, at least 263 people have died from complications caused by the virus worldwide. Nearly 60,000 people have been infected.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>United States</name>
                <start>35</start>
                <end>48</end>
                <lat>40</lat>
                <lon>-100</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Buffalo</name>
                <start>90</start>
                <end>97</end>
                <lat>42.90</lat>
                <lon>-78.84</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Buffalo,_New_York</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>New York</name>
                <start>99</start>
                <end>107</end>
                <lat>43</lat>
                <lon>-75</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_York_(state)</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Buffalo</name>
                <start>264</start>
                <end>271</end>
                <lat>42.90</lat>
                <lon>-78.84</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Buffalo,_New_York</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Buffalo</name>
                <start>807</start>
                <end>814</end>
                <lat>42.90</lat>
                <lon>-78.84</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Buffalo,_New_York</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Buffalo</name>
                <start>1237</start>
                <end>1244</end>
                <lat>42.90</lat>
                <lon>-78.84</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Buffalo,_New_York</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/At_least_71_deaths_in_Mexico_%27likely_linked%27_to_swine_flu_outbreak</source>
        <text>
Officials in Mexico are asking citizens to take actions in order to minimize the spread of the swine flu outbreak. Citizens are urged to stay away from large crowds, avoid kissing people and stay at least 6 feet (1.8 meters) away from one another. Additionally, all schools and universities in Mexico City have been closed indefinitely. In addition, at least twenty people in the United States have been infected with the disease, causing the government to issue a "national public health emergency." On Monday, Mexican officials reported that at least 100 deaths in their country were "likely linked" to the swine flu. Dr. Jose A. Cordova Villalobos, the health secretary of Mexico, said that at least 20 of the deaths have been confirmed as swine flu related deaths while the World Health Organization (WHO) says that 71 people have died from complications caused by the disease. Meanwhile, over 1,300 people in Mexico have been hospitalized because of flu-like symptoms since April 13. In New Zealand, 26 students and teachers might have been infected by the flu during their trip to Mexico. Dr. Julia Peters, the clinical director of Auckland Regional Public Health Service, said that at least 22 have shown flu-like symptoms. All of the students and teachers are being quarantined pending test results.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Mexico</name>
                <start>14</start>
                <end>20</end>
                <lat>23</lat>
                <lon>-102</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mexico</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Mexico City</name>
                <start>295</start>
                <end>306</end>
                <lat>19.43</lat>
                <lon>-99.13</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mexico_City</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>United States</name>
                <start>381</start>
                <end>394</end>
                <lat>40</lat>
                <lon>-100</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Mexico</name>
                <start>677</start>
                <end>683</end>
                <lat>23</lat>
                <lon>-102</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mexico</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Mexico</name>
                <start>915</start>
                <end>921</end>
                <lat>23</lat>
                <lon>-102</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mexico</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>New Zealand</name>
                <start>993</start>
                <end>1004</end>
                <lat>-42</lat>
                <lon>174</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_Zealand</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Four_people_die_after_contracting_H1N1_swine_flu_virus_in_West_Midlands,_England</source>
        <text>Four people from the NHS West Midlands in England have died after contracting the H1N1 swine flu virus. With these deaths, the number of people that have been killed in the West Midlands from the disease has now increased to 19. NHS West Midlands has said that the number of people admitted to hospitals in the region with the disease this week was 203, whereas last week there were 146. It was also said that the number of inpatients taken into hospitals in the area was 95 from this Wednesday onwards. Dr. Rashmi Shukla, the regional director of Public Health in the National Health Service, said about the incident: "We would expect to see a rise in respiratory illness, such as swine flu, at this time of year, and we would like to remind people that they should continue to adhere to good respiratory and hand hygiene practices to reduce chances of the virus spreading.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>England</name>
                <start>43</start>
                <end>50</end>
                <lat>51.5</lat>
                <lon>-0.11</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/England</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>West Midlands</name>
                <start>174</start>
                <end>187</end>
                <lat>52.47</lat>
                <lon>-2.29</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/West_Midlands_(region)</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Gaza_Strip_reports_first_swine_flu_cases</source>
        <text>Health officials in the Gaza Strip confirmed the territory's first five cases of H1N1 swine flu earlier today. The territory's Health Ministry is working with the World Health Organisation (WHO) to obtain the supplies needed to treat the potentially deadly virus. Neighbouring Israel has a blockade on Gaza, and Egypt restricts movement across its border with the territory as well. Health officials say that isolation likely kept the H1N1 virus from affecting Gaza sooner. Mahmoud Daher, a senior official for the WHO, said that Gaza has around 1,000 vaccine doses for the 8,000 medical workers in the territory. West Bank Health Ministry official Asad Ramlawi, however, commented that an additional one million doses would be delivered to the area at the end of the year.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Gaza Strip</name>
                <start>25</start>
                <end>35</end>
                <lat>31.41</lat>
                <lon>34.33</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gaza_Strip</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Israel</name>
                <start>278</start>
                <end>284</end>
                <lat>31</lat>
                <lon>35</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Israel</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Gaza</name>
                <start>303</start>
                <end>307</end>
                <lat>31.41</lat>
                <lon>34.33</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gaza_Strip</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Egypt</name>
                <start>313</start>
                <end>318</end>
                <lat>26</lat>
                <lon>30</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Egypt</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Gaza</name>
                <start>462</start>
                <end>466</end>
                <lat>31.41</lat>
                <lon>34.33</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gaza_Strip</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Gaza</name>
                <start>531</start>
                <end>535</end>
                <lat>31.41</lat>
                <lon>34.33</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gaza_Strip</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>West Bank</name>
                <start>615</start>
                <end>624</end>
                <lat>32</lat>
                <lon>35.38</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/West_Bank</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Kenya_confirms_first_swine_flu_case</source>
        <text>A British medical student has become the first confirmed case of swine flu in Kenya, east Africa. The student, who was in a group of 33, was in Kenya to attend a series of medical camps in Nyanza province. The whole group is currently quarantined in their hotel in Kisumu while undergoing treatment. A second suspected case involving a Kenyan woman who had just arrived from India was put in isolation at Kenyatta National Hospital in the capital Nairobi pending laboratory results. Over the weekend there was panic in the capital as mobile text messages circulated warning people to stay away from Sarit centre, a popular commercial establishment where another suspected case had been diagnosed. The patient's test results however came back negative for the H1N1 virus. Kenya has maintained strong ties with Britain since gaining independence in 1962. Direct flights to London operate regularly. There are fears that the high tourism season which begins this month and runs into September will be adversely affected even as the global recession rages on. The tourism sector is yet to make a full recovery after the country almost slid into a civil war following a disputed general election two years ago, which forced the international community to intervene. A cholera epidemic sweeping across the country has exacerbated the situation, killing at least 80 people since March and setting the stage for a major scare. In recent years Kenya has received large numbers of tourists most of whom troop to Kogelo in Nyanza province to visit the ancestral home and family of the current US president's late father Hussein Obama. There are plans to put up a museum there in his honour. This has made the region extremely susceptible to the current flu pandemic.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Kenya</name>
                <start>79</start>
                <end>84</end>
                <lat>1</lat>
                <lon>38</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kenya</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Kenya</name>
                <start>145</start>
                <end>150</end>
                <lat>1</lat>
                <lon>38</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kenya</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Nyanza</name>
                <start>190</start>
                <end>196</end>
                <lat>-0.5</lat>
                <lon>34.66</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nyanza_Province</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Kisumu</name>
                <start>266</start>
                <end>272</end>
                <lat>-0.1</lat>
                <lon>34.75</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kisumu</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>India</name>
                <start>376</start>
                <end>381</end>
                <lat>21</lat>
                <lon>78</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/India</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Nairobi</name>
                <start>448</start>
                <end>455</end>
                <lat>-1.2</lat>
                <lon>36.81</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nairobi</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Kenya</name>
                <start>772</start>
                <end>777</end>
                <lat>1</lat>
                <lon>38</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kenya</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Britain</name>
                <start>810</start>
                <end>817</end>
                <lat>55</lat>
                <lon>-3</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Kingdom</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>London</name>
                <start>872</start>
                <end>878</end>
                <lat>51.50</lat>
                <lon>-0.12</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/London</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Kenya</name>
                <start>1436</start>
                <end>1441</end>
                <lat>1</lat>
                <lon>38</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kenya</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Kogelo</name>
                <start>1503</start>
                <end>1509</end>
                <lat>-0.01</lat>
                <lon>34.34</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nyang%27oma_Kogelo</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Nyanza</name>
                <start>1513</start>
                <end>1519</end>
                <lat>-0.5</lat>
                <lon>34.66</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nyanza_Province</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Mutated_strain_of_H1N1_virus_detected_in_US_and_Norway</source>
        <text>Health officials in both the United States and Norway have confirmed the presence of a mutated strain of the H1N1, swine flu virus in several patients in the countries. The mutation is resistant to current treatments for H1N1 such as tamiflu, oseltamivir and zanamivir. At least three patients in Norway were confirmed to have the mutated strain of H1N1, with two of the cases being fatal. Health officials say the three cases are not related and isolated from one another. At least four new cases of the mutation were detected in patients at Duke University Medical Center in North Carolina. Three of the four cases were fatal, but the same patients also had severe underlying illnesses before they caught influenza. Two prior cases of the mutation in the same state, were reported in the Summer of 2008. Health officials say none of the cases are related. Director of the Center for Disease Control's Center for Immunization and Respiratory Diseases, Anne Schuchat says the cases are appearing in the U.S. "sporadically." "It's just too soon for us to say what this is going to mean long term. It's an important finding for the influenza virologists, and they're looking into it. [The mutation] has no implications for how good the match of the vaccine is and no implications for treatment with antiviral medicine," said Schuchat during a press conference. Health officials in other countries such as Mexico, China, Japan, Ukraine and Brazil, also report cases of the mutation.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>United States</name>
                <start>30</start>
                <end>43</end>
                <lat>40</lat>
                <lon>-100</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Norway</name>
                <start>48</start>
                <end>54</end>
                <lat>61</lat>
                <lon>8</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Norway</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Norway</name>
                <start>298</start>
                <end>304</end>
                <lat>61</lat>
                <lon>8</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Norway</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>North Carolina</name>
                <start>578</start>
                <end>592</end>
                <lat>35.5</lat>
                <lon>-80</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/North_Carolina</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>U.S.</name>
                <start>1004</start>
                <end>1008</end>
                <lat>40</lat>
                <lon>-100</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Mexico</name>
                <start>1404</start>
                <end>1410</end>
                <lat>23</lat>
                <lon>-102</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mexico</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>China</name>
                <start>1412</start>
                <end>1417</end>
                <lat>35</lat>
                <lon>103</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/China</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Japan</name>
                <start>1419</start>
                <end>1424</end>
                <lat>35</lat>
                <lon>136</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Japan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Ukraine</name>
                <start>1426</start>
                <end>1433</end>
                <lat>49</lat>
                <lon>32</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ukraine</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Brazil</name>
                <start>1438</start>
                <end>1444</end>
                <lat>-10</lat>
                <lon>-52</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brazil</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Saudi_Arabia_fears_Hajj_swine_flu_outbreak_as_four_pilgrims_die</source>
        <text>As the annual Muslim Hajj pilgrimage to Mecca gets underway, Saudi Arabian authorities have expressed concern swine flu could impact pilgrims. Four, with underlying health issues, have already died. Two men and a woman in their seventies and a seventeen-year-old girl have died, according to the Health Ministry. The men from India and Sudan, the older woman from Morocco, and the teen from Nigeria. None were vaccinated against the virus. One died in Mecca, the others in Medina. All had conditions including cancer and respiratory ailments. The World Health Organisation puts the current swine flu death toll at 6,750. Four more people are in Saudi hospitals in critical condition and a further twelve are recovering in hospital. Each year around three million make the pilgrimage. And, Saudi authorities are concerned about the possible spread of the virus. At least one pilgrimage to Mecca is deemed mandatory for every Muslim capable of doing so. Fifteen thousand extra medical staff are deployed, ports and airports screen incomers with thermal cameras, and hundreds of extra hospital beds have been set aside. Visa requirements specify only those vaccinated against the flu strain can apply. In September, Egypt forbade hundreds of Muslims from leaving Cairo for the Hajj after an Egyptian woman returning from a more minor pilgrimage last July became the first swine flu fatality in both Africa and the Middle East. For Ramadan, pilgrimage to Saudi Arabia was banned by Iran for the same reason.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Mecca</name>
                <start>41</start>
                <end>46</end>
                <lat>21.41</lat>
                <lon>39.81</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mecca</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>India</name>
                <start>327</start>
                <end>332</end>
                <lat>21</lat>
                <lon>78</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/India</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Sudan</name>
                <start>337</start>
                <end>342</end>
                <lat>15</lat>
                <lon>32</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sudan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Morocco</name>
                <start>365</start>
                <end>372</end>
                <lat>32</lat>
                <lon>-6</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Morocco</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Nigeria</name>
                <start>392</start>
                <end>399</end>
                <lat>8</lat>
                <lon>10</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nigeria</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Mecca</name>
                <start>453</start>
                <end>458</end>
                <lat>21.41</lat>
                <lon>39.81</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mecca</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Medina</name>
                <start>474</start>
                <end>480</end>
                <lat>24.46</lat>
                <lon>39.6</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Medina</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Mecca</name>
                <start>889</start>
                <end>894</end>
                <lat>21.41</lat>
                <lon>39.81</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mecca</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Egypt</name>
                <start>1214</start>
                <end>1219</end>
                <lat>26</lat>
                <lon>30</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Egypt</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Cairo</name>
                <start>1261</start>
                <end>1266</end>
                <lat>30.04</lat>
                <lon>31.23</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cairo</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Saudi Arabia</name>
                <start>1452</start>
                <end>1464</end>
                <lat>24</lat>
                <lon>45</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saudi_Arabia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Iran</name>
                <start>1479</start>
                <end>1483</end>
                <lat>32</lat>
                <lon>53</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iran</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/School_closed_after_five-year-old_boy_dies_from_suspected_swine_flu_in_Buckinghamshire,_England</source>
        <text>A five-year-old boy has been suspected to have died from the H1N1 swine flu virus in Buckinghamshire, England. The boy came from Emberton School, which now has just 29 pupils attending. Health tests are currently being carried out to determine whether or not the child did indeed die from the virus. He was admitted to a hospital in Milton Keynes, but later died in the early hours of Sunday morning. At present, the individual remains unidentified. Steve Dunning is the principal in the school. Speaking to BBC Three Counties Radio, Dunning said: "The staff of Emberton School are very saddened to learn of the death of one of their pupils who was a confident, delightful and happy student and will be missed greatly. At this time we are focusing on supporting the children and parents in our small village community. I have spoken directly with the mother and passed on the condolences of all the staff and governors at the school."</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Buckinghamshire</name>
                <start>86</start>
                <end>101</end>
                <lat>51.83</lat>
                <lon>-0.83</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Buckinghamshire</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>England</name>
                <start>103</start>
                <end>110</end>
                <lat>51.5</lat>
                <lon>-0.11</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/England</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Milton Keynes</name>
                <start>334</start>
                <end>347</end>
                <lat>52.04</lat>
                <lon>-0.76</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Milton_Keynes</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
</articles>