<articles>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Philippines_is_culling_6500_hogs_after_Reston_ebolavirus_outbreak</source>
        <text>The Philippine Department of Agriculture (DA), local health and agricultural teams Sunday have started slaughtering, burning and burying roughly 6,500 hogs at a farm in Pandi, Bulacan in Central Luzon on Sunday after three farm workers became infected with Reston ebolavirus (ERV) of the virus group Ebola, as a precautionary measure and to protect the local livestock industry. "We culled around 300 heads—piglets and growers—in two and a half hours; we tried to start the process at 5 p.m. Sunday; after three hours we disposed of 442 hogs; that includes transporting the hogs to an area in the farm where they will be disposed of; with this rate and with some improvements in the procedure tomorrow, we expect to complete the depopulation by Wednesday,” Bureau of Animal Industry (BAI) head Davinio Catbagan said. "With the problems we encountered last night, we may go beyond Thursday," he added.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Pandi</name>
                <start>170</start>
                <end>175</end>
                <lat>14.87</lat>
                <lon>120.95</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pandi,_Bulacan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Central Luzon</name>
                <start>188</start>
                <end>201</end>
                <lat>15.47</lat>
                <lon>120.75</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Central_Luzon</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Bulacan</name>
                <start>177</start>
                <end>184</end>
                <lat>15</lat>
                <lon>121.08</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bulacan</page>
                </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Philippines_is_culling_6500_hogs_after_Reston_ebolavirus_outbreak</source>
        <text>The agriculture officials earlier announced that the depopulation will be carried out in a "humane" manner, following current Office international des épizooties (OIE) procedures that ensure protection of animal welfare in the Bulacan farm. According to Philippine Department of Health (DOH) Secretary Francisco Duque, the quarantine of the hog farm in Palauig, Manaoag, Pangasinan has been lifted after finding no traces of viral transmission. According to Yap, test results conducted by a joint mission of FAO, the World Animal Health Organization, WHO and their local counterparts, reveal that viral transmission continues to exist in Pandi hog farms, which is only 0.5% of the 13 million pigs raised throughout the country. DOH officials also say a pig farm worker in Cabanatuan in Nueva Ecija, who had no direct contact with sick hogs, has tested positive for Immunoglobulin G antibodies against the Reston ebolavirus, which is non-lethal, unlike the Zaïre, Bundibugyo, Côte d'Ivoire and Sudan strains, according to FAO.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Bulacan</name>
                <start>228</start>
                <end>235</end>
                <lat>15</lat>
                <lon>121.08</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bulacan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Manaoag</name>
                <start>363</start>
                <end>370</end>
                <lat>16.04</lat>
                <lon>120.48</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Manaoag,_Pangasinan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Pangasinan</name>
                <start>372</start>
                <end>382</end>
                <lat>15.92</lat>
                <lon>120.33</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pangasinan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Palauig</name>
                <start>354</start>
                <end>361</end>
                <lat>15.43</lat>
                <lon>120.05</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palauig</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Pandi</name>
                <start>639</start>
                <end>644</end>
                <lat>14.87</lat>
                <lon>120.95</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pandi,_Bulacan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Cabanatuan</name>
                <start>773</start>
                <end>783</end>
                <lat>15.48</lat>
                <lon>120.97</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cabanatuan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Nueva Ecija</name>
                <start>787</start>
                <end>798</end>
                <lat>15.58</lat>
                <lon>121</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nueva_Ecija</page>
            </location>
    </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Philippines_is_culling_6500_hogs_after_Reston_ebolavirus_outbreak</source>
        <text>Local police has also arrested four vendors and seized their 3,000 kilos of "botcha" (rotten pork meat or "double dead meat") at MC Market in Balintawak, Quezon City Wednesday evening, and allegedly delivered from Bulacan. The four suspects were charged for violation of the Consumer Act of the Philippines and Republic Act 9296 or the Meat Inspection Code. In December, international experts initially probed outbreak among Philippine pigs, wherein about 6,000 pigs at Pandi and Talavera farms were tested for the Reston ebolavirus. "There is no salmonella outbreak in Eastern Visayas, Region 8, said Dr. Archie Lluz, Chief of Regional Animal Disease and Diagnostic Laboratory of the Department of Agriculture in the region. But hog specimens from Tacloban and Babatngon, where 270 swine deaths and cases of sick pigs were reported, were examined by lab tests. The results revealed cutaneous "Pasteurella hemolytica", a type of bacterial infection which causes swine deaths due to loss of appetite, dehydration, fever and diarrhea.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Balintawak</name>
                <start>143</start>
                <end>153</end>
                <lat>14.63</lat>
                <lon>121.03</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Balintawak</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Quezon City</name>
                <start>155</start>
                <end>166</end>
                <lat>14.63</lat>
                <lon>121.03</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quezon_City</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Bulacan</name>
                <start>215</start>
                <end>222</end>
                <lat>15</lat>
                <lon>121.08</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bulacan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Pandi</name>
                <start>471</start>
                <end>476</end>
                <lat>14.87</lat>
                <lon>120.95</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pandi,_Bulacan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Talavera</name>
                <start>481</start>
                <end>489</end>
                <lat>15.58</lat>
                <lon>120.91</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Talavera,_Nueva_Ecija</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Eastern Visayas</name>
                <start>571</start>
                <end>586</end>
                <lat>11.24</lat>
                <lon>125.05</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eastern_Visayas</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Tacloban</name>
                <start>750</start>
                <end>758</end>
                <lat>11.24</lat>
                <lon>125</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tacloban</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Babatngon</name>
                <start>763</start>
                <end>772</end>
                <lat>11.42</lat>
                <lon>124.85</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Babatngon,_Leyte</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/US_soldier_who_died_after_serving_in_Liberia_tests_negative_for_Ebola</source>
        <text>Tests yesterday proved negative for Ebola on the remains of a US soldier who died in Texas after deployment to Liberia. The 24-year-old had been monitoring potential symptoms of the disease. The Killeen Police Department continues to investigate the soldier's death. He has not been named publicly. He died at his home near Fort Hood military base. Fort Hood said the soldier had been involved in constructing a hospital to combat Ebola in Africa, and returned to the US on emergency leave earlier this month.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Texas</name>
                <start>86</start>
                <end>91</end>
                <lat>31</lat>
                <lon>-100</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Texas</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Liberia</name>
                <start>112</start>
                <end>119</end>
                <lat>6.5</lat>
                <lon>-9.5</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liberia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>US</name>
                <start>63</start>
                <end>65</end>
                <lat>40</lat>
                <lon>-100</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Fort Hood</name>
                <start>325</start>
                <end>334</end>
                <lat>31.13</lat>
                <lon>-97.78</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fort_Hood</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Patient_under_evaluation_with_Ebola-like_symptoms_in_Washington_D.C.</source>
        <text>
A patient was admitted to a hospital in Washington, D.C. after showing Ebola-like symptoms, according to a statement yesterday by hospital spokeswoman Kerry-Ann Hamilton. Shady Grove Adventist Hospital in Rockville, Maryland admitted another patient with Ebola-like symptoms, but health officials there yesterday night later determined this person had malaria, not the Ebola virus. At the peak of Ebola countermeasures in Nigeria, almost 900 people there were monitored for the virus after contacting someone who was already sick.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Washington</name>
                <start>41</start>
                <end>51</end>
                <lat>38.90</lat>
                <lon>-77.01</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Washington,_D.C.</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Rockville</name>
                <start>206</start>
                <end>215</end>
                <lat>39.08</lat>
                <lon>-77.14</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rockville,_Maryland</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Maryland</name>
                <start>217</start>
                <end>225</end>
                <lat>39</lat>
                <lon>-76.7</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maryland</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Nigeria</name>
                <start>423</start>
                <end>430</end>
                <lat>8</lat>
                <lon>10</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nigeria</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Scottish_Ebola_nurse_Pauline_Cafferkey_%27critically_ill%27_says_Royal_Free_Hospital</source>
        <text>The Royal Free Hospital in London yesterday said a nurse suffering with complications after Ebola, Pauline Cafferkey, is "critically ill" after her condition deteriorated. Cafferkey, 39, was readmitted to an isolation unit at the Royal Free on the night of October 8–9 where she had spent time earlier in the year after contracting Ebola in Sierra Leone whilst treating patients with the infection. Cafferkey visited an out of hours GP clinic on October 5 where her symptoms were not linked to Ebola, before deciding to go to the Queen Elizabeth University Hospital in Glasgow on October 6 where she was treated at the hospital's infectious diseases unit. Two days later, she was flown by plane to the Royal Free. She is the only person known to suffer with Ebola in this way for a second time, which can remain in the body after an initial recovery.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>London</name>
                <start>28</start>
                <end>34</end>
                <lat>51.50</lat>
                <lon>-0.12</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/London</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Sierra Leone</name>
                <start>342</start>
                <end>354</end>
                <lat>8.5</lat>
                <lon>-11.5</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sierra_Leone</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Glasgow</name>
                <start>570</start>
                <end>577</end>
                <lat>55.85</lat>
                <lon>-4.25</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glasgow</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Bird_flu_outbreak_kills_birds_in_Krasnodar_region</source>
        <text>
Krasnodar, Russia officials said yesterday they have found roughly 4,000 dead wild birds in the region. Doctors identified the disease as bird flu subtype H5. Officials said the outbreak originated with coots in water reservoirs at the west of the region. The Krasnodar leading veterinary physician, George Gzhailidi, said the bird flu outbreak originated with coots in the Temryuk and Anapa. The region governor Alexander Nikolayevich Tkachyov said, "At risk is the health and safety of people, of everybody who lives in the region.
        </text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Krasnodar</name>
                <start>1</start>
                <end>10</end>
                <lat>45.06</lat>
                <lon>38.96</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Krasnodar</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Russia</name>
                <start>12</start>
                <end>18</end>
                <lat>60</lat>
                <lon>90</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Temryuk</name>
                <start>375</start>
                <end>382</end>
                <lat>45.26</lat>
                <lon>37.38</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Temryuk</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Anapa</name>
                <start>387</start>
                <end>392</end>
                <lat>44.88</lat>
                <lon>37.31</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anapa</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Krasnodar</name>
                <start>261</start>
                <end>270</end>
                <lat>45.06</lat>
                <lon>38.96</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Krasnodar</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Taiwan_culls_18000_chickens_due_to_H5N2_virus_outbreak</source>
        <text>
New outbreaks of H5N2 have been confirmed in Taiwan. Lujhu is a rural township in northwestern Taoyuan. It is located at kilometer 49 of the Highway no.1, close to the Taiwan Taoyuan International Airport (IATA: TPE). Kaohsiung is a county in southern Taiwan administered as a County of Taiwan. Mr Huang Kwo-ching, deputy director of the Bureau of Animal and Plant Health Inspection and Quarantine, however, said, "we took the most stringent measures in dealing with the episode as according to the rules of the World Organisation for Animal Health (OIE), there was no need to slaughter those chickens."</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Taiwan</name>
                <start>46</start>
                <end>52</end>
                <lat>25.03</lat>
                <lon>121.63</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taiwan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Lujhu</name>
                <start>54</start>
                <end>59</end>
                <lat>25.03</lat>
                <lon>121.28</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luzhu_District,_Taoyuan</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Taoyuan</name>
                <start>96</start>
                <end>103</end>
                <lat>24.98</lat>
                <lon>121.31</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taoyuan_District</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Kaohsiung</name>
                <start>219</start>
                <end>228</end>
                <lat>22.63</lat>
                <lon>120.26</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kaohsiung</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Taiwan</name>
                <start>253</start>
                <end>259</end>
                <lat>25.03</lat>
                <lon>121.63</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taiwan</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Wild_Canadian_Goose_tests_positive_for_H5N1_in_England</source>
        <text>The H5N1 Avian Flu virus has been found in a dead wild Canadian Goose in Abbotsbury Swannery in Dorset, England. This is the eleventh case of the virus turning up in wild birds. The goose was discovered on February 25, 2008. "The finding of more cases in wild birds is not unexpected ... We are currently considering whether any additional restrictions are necessary in the area," said the United Kingdom's Health Ministry in a statement to the media. As a result of the finding, poultry movement has now been restricted by the Department for the Environment, Food and Rural Affairs (DEFRA) in the areas surrounding the Swannery. The removal of all birds, dead or alive from any property now requires a license. DEFRA says the restrictions will expire no earlier than 31 days.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Dorset</name>
                <start>97</start>
                <end>103</end>
                <lat>50.83</lat>
                <lon>-2.33</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dorset</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>England</name>
                <start>105</start>
                <end>112</end>
                <lat>51.5</lat>
                <lon>-0.11</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/England</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>United Kingdom</name>
                <start>391</start>
                <end>405</end>
                <lat>55</lat>
                <lon>-3</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Kingdom</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/%22Low_pathogenic%22_H5N1_Bird_Flu_virus_found_in_wild_ducks_in_Maryland_and_Pennsylvania</source>
        <text>The United States Department of Agriculture has announced that a "low pathogenic" form of the H5N1 Avian Flu has been found in fecal samples taken from wild Mallard ducks located in Queen Anne's County in Maryland and in Crawford County located in Pennsylvania. Officials stress that the strain is of no risk to humans. Samples from the ducks in Pennsylvania were taken on August 28. "Testing has ruled out the possibility of this being the highly pathogenic H5N1 strain that has spread through birds in Asia, Europe and Africa. Test results thus far indicate this is low pathogenic avian influenza, which poses no risk to human health. The fecal samples were collected on August 2 from resident wild ducks in Queen Anne's County, Maryland, as part of a research project conducted by Ohio State University. The fecal samples came from mallards that showed no signs of sickness," said the USDA in a statement on its website. Ducks in Pennsylvania also had shown no signs of being sick.
        </text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Queen Anne's County</name>
                <start>183</start>
                <end>202</end>
                <lat>39.03</lat>
                <lon>-76.08</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Queen_Anne%27s_County,_Maryland</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Crawford County</name>
                <start>222</start>
                <end>237</end>
                <lat>41.68</lat>
                <lon>-80.11</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crawford_County,_Pennsylvania</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Pennsylvania</name>
                <start>249</start>
                <end>261</end>
                <lat>41</lat>
                <lon>-77.5</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pennsylvania</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Pennsylvania</name>
                <start>347</start>
                <end>359</end>
                <lat>41</lat>
                <lon>-77.5</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pennsylvania</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Queen Anne's County</name>
                <start>711</start>
                <end>730</end>
                <lat>39.03</lat>
                <lon>-76.08</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Queen_Anne%27s_County,_Maryland</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Maryland</name>
                <start>732</start>
                <end>740</end>
                <lat>39</lat>
                <lon>-76.7</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maryland</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Pennsylvania</name>
                <start>934</start>
                <end>946</end>
                <lat>41</lat>
                <lon>-77.5</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pennsylvania</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Avian_flu_found_in_eastern_Canada</source>
        <text>Canada's Broadcasting Corporation reports that a case of avian flu has been discovered in a bird in the Eastern province of Prince Edward Island. The case was discovered in a gosling found in the community of O'Leary and confirmed at the Atlantic Veterinary College in Charlottetown. The announcement was made in a press release issued by the government of Prince Edward Island. Chief Health Officer for PEI, Dr. Lamont Sweet, said, "From the information we have received, there is a low risk of human illness at the present time." He went on to suggest that people in West Prince who have contact with domestic or wild birds who may be experiencing flu-like symptoms should consult their physician.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Canada</name>
                <start>1</start>
                <end>7</end>
                <lat>60</lat>
                <lon>-95</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canada</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Prince Edward Island</name>
                <start>125</start>
                <end>145</end>
                <lat>46.25</lat>
                <lon>-63</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prince_Edward_Island</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Charlottetown</name>
                <start>270</start>
                <end>283</end>
                <lat>46.23</lat>
                <lon>-63.12</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlottetown</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Prince Edward Island</name>
                <start>358</start>
                <end>378</end>
                <lat>46.25</lat>
                <lon>-63</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prince_Edward_Island</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/%22Aggressive%22_Bird_Flu_found_in_Sweden</source>
        <text>An "aggressive" strain of Avian Flu has been detected in two tufted ducks in Oskarshamn, southeast Sweden. This makes Sweden the ninth country in the EU to confirm Avian Flu on their soil. Some 35–40 wild birds were found dead. The birds were brought to Uppsala, where an analysis confirmed the presence of an "aggressive" form of Avian Flu. Tests at a laboratory in the UK will later eventually confirm whether the birds died of the lethal H5N1. Sweden's Minister of Agriculture, Ann-Christin Nykvist, said at a press conference the discovery was "serious but not unexpected." Sweden has been on high alert since the virus was found on the German island Rügen in the Baltic Sea.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Oskarshamn</name>
                <start>78</start>
                <end>88</end>
                <lat>57.26</lat>
                <lon>16.45</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oskarshamn</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Sweden</name>
                <start>100</start>
                <end>106</end>
                <lat>63</lat>
                <lon>16</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sweden</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Uppsala</name>
                <start>255</start>
                <end>262</end>
                <lat>59.85</lat>
                <lon>17.64</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uppsala</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>UK</name>
                <start>372</start>
                <end>374</end>
                <lat>55</lat>
                <lon>-3</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Kingdom</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Rügen</name>
                <start>656</start>
                <end>661</end>
                <lat>54.41</lat>
                <lon>13.4</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/R%C3%BCgen</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Baltic Sea</name>
                <start>669</start>
                <end>679</end>
                <lat>58</lat>
                <lon>20</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baltic_Sea</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Avian_Flu_is_confirmed_in_Egypt</source>
        <text>Yesterday February 17, 2006, the World Health Organisation officially declared presence of the H5N1 strain of the avian flu virus in Egypt. "There is avian flu now in Egypt," Hassan el Bushra, regional adviser for emerging diseases at the eastern Mediterranean regional office of the WHO said. His response was to the reported presence of H5N1 virus in dead birds in three areas in Egypt - namely Cairo, Giza, and Al-Minya. Today February 18, 2006, a responsible source from Egyptian ministry of health announced reporting of another 25 cases of infected birds in Al-Minya with aftermath of 35 confirmed cases between birds, yet there are no human cases reported.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Egypt</name>
                <start>134</start>
                <end>139</end>
                <lat>26</lat>
                <lon>30</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Egypt</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Mediterranean</name>
                <start>248</start>
                <end>261</end>
                <lat>35</lat>
                <lon>18</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mediterranean_Sea</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Cairo</name>
                <start>398</start>
                <end>403</end>
                <lat>30.04</lat>
                <lon>31.23</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cairo</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Giza</name>
                <start>405</start>
                <end>409</end>
                <lat>30.01</lat>
                <lon>31.21</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Giza</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Al-Minya</name>
                <start>415</start>
                <end>423</end>
                <lat>28.11</lat>
                <lon>30.74</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minya,_Egypt</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Bird_Flu_confirmed_in_1,000_UK_turkeys</source>
        <text>1,000 turkeys in the United Kingdom have been confirmed by UK government officials as dying of a strain of avian flu and a further 1,600 have died since the infection was initially reported. The birds, believed to be from a Bernard Matthews owned farm in Suffolk fell ill and died this week after contracting the H5 strain of the flu. It is likely that all other poultry on the farm will be culled. The department were swift in carrying out a full investigation and sent samples to be tested at facilities in Weybridge. This report comes less than a year after a mass culling of 50,000 birds in Norfolk after an outbreak of the H7 strain.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>United Kingdom</name>
                <start>22</start>
                <end>36</end>
                <lat>55</lat>
                <lon>-3</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Kingdom</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Suffolk</name>
                <start>256</start>
                <end>263</end>
                <lat>52.16</lat>
                <lon>1</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suffolk</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Norfolk</name>
                <start>596</start>
                <end>603</end>
                <lat>52.66</lat>
                <lon>1</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Norfolk</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Weybridge</name>
                <start>510</start>
                <end>519</end>
                <lat>51.36</lat>
                <lon>-0.45</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Weybridge</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Bird_Flu_kills_40th_Indonesian</source>
        <text>The World Health Organisation confirmed the death of a five-year-old boy on June 16 was due to bird flu. This is the 40th confirmed Indonesian death due to bird flu. The boy died in Tulungagung, East Java province, after being admitted to hospital on June 8. There was a dead chicken 15 metres from his home. The death was confirmed by a WHO laboratory in Hong Kong. Deaths due to bird flu have steadily risen since its outbreak in Indonesia in 2003. This year they have recorded the highest death toll in the world.
        </text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Tulungagung</name>
                <start>183</start>
                <end>194</end>
                <lat>-8.06</lat>
                <lon>111.9</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tulungagung_Regency</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>East Java</name>
                <start>196</start>
                <end>205</end>
                <lat>-7.26</lat>
                <lon>112.75</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/East_Java</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Hong Kong</name>
                <start>357</start>
                <end>366</end>
                <lat>22.3</lat>
                <lon>114.2</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hong_Kong</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Indonesia</name>
                <start>433</start>
                <end>442</end>
                <lat>-5</lat>
                <lon>120</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indonesia</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Bird_flu_spreading_through_Indonesia_and_China</source>
        <text>Two Indonesian women, 23 and 27, have tested positive for the H5N1 strain of avian influenza. They are in "serious condition but seem to be improving," said Hariadi Wibisono, a senior health ministry official. They are being treated in the designated bird flu hospital, Sulianti Suroso in eastern Jakarta. It is believed that both women had contact with infected poultry. This brings Indonesia's number of confirmed cases of the virus to 25. A 26 year old female farmer in Fujian, China whose surname is Lin, also has the deadly H5N1 virus. She was admitted to the hospital in January, but it was only confirmed on Wednesday that she had the virus. Some of the people that have come in close contact with the woman are under observation by local health officials. Her current condition is reported as stable. This is China's eleventh confirmed case of the virus.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Jakarta</name>
                <start>298</start>
                <end>305</end>
                <lat>-6.2</lat>
                <lon>106.81</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jakarta</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Indonesia</name>
                <start>385</start>
                <end>394</end>
                <lat>-5</lat>
                <lon>120</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indonesia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Fujian</name>
                <start>474</start>
                <end>480</end>
                <lat>25.9</lat>
                <lon>118.3</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fujian</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>China</name>
                <start>482</start>
                <end>487</end>
                <lat>35</lat>
                <lon>103</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/China</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>China</name>
                <start>818</start>
                <end>823</end>
                <lat>35</lat>
                <lon>103</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/China</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/British_report_says_the_U.K._is_preparing_%27mass_graves%27_for_humans_if_Bird_Flu_mutates</source>
        <text>"Prudent precautionary planning is under way across all elements of the response, including the health service, other essential services and local authorities," said a Home Office spokesman. However; at the moment, the virus only infects humans who have been in close or direct contact with infected poultry. The U.K. also reports that it has stockpiled at least 14.6 million doses of anti-viral medication. The report cautions that vaccines against the virus "will not be available in the first wave of a pandemic" and that the vaccines would not be a "silver bullet." It also states that the local officials are prepared to handle only 48,000 deaths in Wales and in England for a pandemic lasting 15 weeks, however; the reports states further that, "even with ramping local management capacity by 100%, the prudent worst case of 320,000 deaths is projected to lead to a delay of some 17 weeks from death to burial or cremation."</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>U.K.</name>
                <start>314</start>
                <end>318</end>
                <lat>55</lat>
                <lon>-3</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Kingdom</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Wales</name>
                <start>656</start>
                <end>661</end>
                <lat>52.3</lat>
                <lon>-3.6</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wales</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>England</name>
                <start>669</start>
                <end>676</end>
                <lat>51.5</lat>
                <lon>-0.11</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/England</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Chickens_at_a_Norfolk_farm_to_be_culled_after_testing_positive_for_bird_flu</source>
        <text>35,000 chickens at Witford Lodge Farm at Norfolk, England are to be culled after some chickens found dead tested positive for bird flu. Further tests are being carried out to establish which strain of the virus it was, but preliminary results suggest it is not the H5N1 strain, but is instead the H7N7 strain. The birds are being culled as a precautionary measure. The H7N7 strain can be transmitted to humans, but not as easily or as lethally as the H5N1 strain. Previous outbreaks of the H7N7 strain include one from 2003 in the Netherlands, which infected more than 80 people and led to the death of one vet. So far the only positive test for H5N1 in the UK has been a dead swan found in Fife.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Norfolk</name>
                <start>42</start>
                <end>49</end>
                <lat>52.66</lat>
                <lon>1</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Norfolk</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>England</name>
                <start>51</start>
                <end>58</end>
                <lat>51.5</lat>
                <lon>-0.11</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/England</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Netherlands</name>
                <start>532</start>
                <end>543</end>
                <lat>52.31</lat>
                <lon>5.55</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Netherlands</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>UK</name>
                <start>659</start>
                <end>661</end>
                <lat>55</lat>
                <lon>-3</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Kingdom</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Fife</name>
                <start>692</start>
                <end>696</end>
                <lat>56.25</lat>
                <lon>-3.2</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fife</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/China_and_Europe_face_new_avian_flu_outbreaks</source>
        <text>
China has announced a new outbreak of avian flu today along with similar cases in Russia, Romania, and Macedonia. China's news agency reported that 2,600 birds have died of the H5N1 strain in northern China, declaring that the outbreak was found in a breeding facility in Hohhot, the capital of Inner Mongolia. The government maintains the epidemic is under control. Russia is waiting for confirmation that it was the H5N1 strain that killed several hundred ducks near Moscow; if the tests return positive it will be a major spread of the virus across the Ural Mountains, into European Russia. A small village in southern Macedonia also suspects the strain. Plans are already made to kill 10,000 birds to contain the outbreak. Romania confirmed that there has been another outbreak in the Danube Delta area. The strain was confirmed there last weekend, whereupon 4,500 birds were destroyed. H5N1 is the strain scientists fear could be transmitted from human to human, causing a flu pandemic. So far 50 people have died of it, all having worked closely with birds. It is not easy to pass the disease from bird to human.
        </text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>China</name>
                <start>1</start>
                <end>6</end>
                <lat>35</lat>
                <lon>103</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/China</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Russia</name>
                <start>83</start>
                <end>89</end>
                <lat>60</lat>
                <lon>90</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Romania</name>
                <start>91</start>
                <end>98</end>
                <lat>46</lat>
                <lon>25</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Romania</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Macedonia</name>
                <start>104</start>
                <end>113</end>
                <lat>41.6</lat>
                <lon>21.7</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Republic_of_Macedonia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>China</name>
                <start>202</start>
                <end>207</end>
                <lat>35</lat>
                <lon>103</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/China</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Hohhot</name>
                <start>273</start>
                <end>279</end>
                <lat>40.81</lat>
                <lon>111.65</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hohhot</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Inner Mongolia</name>
                <start>296</start>
                <end>310</end>
                <lat>44</lat>
                <lon>113</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inner_Mongolia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Moscow</name>
                <start>470</start>
                <end>476</end>
                <lat>55.75</lat>
                <lon>37.61</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moscow</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Danube Delta</name>
                <start>790</start>
                <end>802</end>
                <lat>45.33</lat>
                <lon>29.5</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Danube_Delta</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Duck_hunters_asked_to_help_monitor_spread_of_Avian_Flu</source>
        <text>Virginia duck and goose hunters, and waterfowl hunters in other parts of the US, might for the first time find themselves approached by state game officials who are testing harvested birds for the presence of Avian Flu. The migratory flyways considered most at risk of disease transmission are on the Pacific side of the Americas in Alaska and the Pacific NorthWest, closest to Asia. The Atlantic flyway shares migratory influence from Europe and Africa where the Avian Flu has also been found. A low pathogenic strain of H5N1 that currently exists in North America is common among waterfowl. Testing for the more virulent strains involves swabbing the bird's throat or rectum.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Virginia</name>
                <start>1</start>
                <end>9</end>
                <lat>37.5</lat>
                <lon>-79</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virginia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>US</name>
                <start>78</start>
                <end>80</end>
                <lat>40</lat>
                <lon>-100</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Alaska</name>
                <start>334</start>
                <end>340</end>
                <lat>64</lat>
                <lon>-150</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alaska</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Europe_restricts_poultry_as_bird_flu_spreads_to_eight_European_nations</source>
        <text>Authorities across Europe have issued restrictions on commercial poultry farms, following the outbreak of bird flu in eight previously unaffected nations. The virus has been found in migratory birds much earlier than had been expected. Tests have confirmed that wild swans in Greece, Bulgaria, Italy, Austria and Germany had died from the deadly H5N1 strain of the virus. Other suspected cases of the virus have been detected in Slovenia, Croatia and Denmark. European health officials had expected wild birds migrating from Africa to Europe in spring to carry the disease into Western Europe. It is thought that swans were migrating from Russia and Ukraine to the Black Sea driven by unusually cold weather. Globally, 91 people have died after contracting the virus from close contact with diseased birds, but the greatest concern for European authorities is that an outbreak will occur among domesticated fowl, destroying local poultry industries. The H5N1 strain of bird flu is highly contagious, and lethal to birds. A single outbreak can kill tens of thousands of birds, and all birds must be culled across a wide region to prevent the spread of the disease.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name>Greece</name>
                <start>277</start>
                <end>283</end>
                <lat>39</lat>
                <lon>22</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greece</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Bulgaria</name>
                <start>285</start>
                <end>293</end>
                <lat>42.75</lat>
                <lon>25.5</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bulgaria</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Italy</name>
                <start>295</start>
                <end>300</end>
                <lat>43</lat>
                <lon>12</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Italy</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Austria</name>
                <start>302</start>
                <end>309</end>
                <lat>47.33</lat>
                <lon>13.33</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Austria</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Germany</name>
                <start>314</start>
                <end>321</end>
                <lat>51</lat>
                <lon>9</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Germany</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Slovenia</name>
                <start>430</start>
                <end>438</end>
                <lat>46.11</lat>
                <lon>14.81</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slovenia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Croatia</name>
                <start>440</start>
                <end>447</end>
                <lat>45.16</lat>
                <lon>15.5</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Croatia</page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name>Denmark</name>
                <start>452</start>
                <end>459</end>
                <lat>56</lat>
                <lon>10</lon>
                <page>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Denmark</page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source>https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Egyptian_woman_becomes_third_to_die_of_bird_flu_in_a_week</source>
        <text>
A woman in Egypt has died of the H5N1 strain of bird flu. H5N1 has killed two other Egyptian women already this week, bringing the total dead of the virus in Egypt to 18. Fardous Mahammed Hadad was taken into hospital on Sunday after having difficulty breathing and developing a high fever, and subsequently tested positive for bird flu. She died today, at the age of 36. As well as Hadad, who was from Menoufia, this week saw the deaths of Fatima Fathi Mohammed from Daqahliya and Ola Youness Mohammed from Beni Suef. They all died from H5N1; Ola Youness Mohammed's case was Egypt's first since July. In addition, the World Health Organisation says two further woman are infected without giving any further details; the United Nations health agency says that on December 24 a 50-year-old woman was hospitalised and remains in critical condition, whilst a chicken seller, 22, is recovering from the infection in intensive care.</text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
    <article>
        <source></source>
        <text></text>
        <locations>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
            <location>
                <name></name>
                <start></start>
                <end></end>
                <lat></lat>
                <lon></lon>
                <page></page>
            </location>
        </locations>
    </article>
</articles>